-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：pizzamx psychomel
校对：pizzamx
他正值壮年…
He was growing into middle age...
…住在森林大道的一座平房里
...and was living then in a bungalow
on Woodland Avenue.
他坐在摇椅里…
He installed himself in a rocking chair...
…在暮色里抽着雪茄…
...and smoked a cigar down
in the evenings...
…他的妻子在围裙上擦着粉红的双手…
...as his wife wiped her pink hands
on an apron...
…和他们的两个孩子说着什么
...and reported happily
on their two children.
孩子们熟悉父亲的双腿…
His children knew his legs...
…还有他的胡子扎在自己脸上的感觉
...the sting of his mustache
against their cheeks.
但他们不知道父亲如何谋生
也不知道为什么经常要搬家
They didn't know how their father made
his living or why they so often moved.
他们甚至不知道父亲的名字
They didn't even know
their father's name.
在市政府的名录上
他叫做托马斯・霍华德
He was listed in the city directory
as Thomas Howard.
走在街上没人认得他…
And he went everywhere unrecognized...
…他时常与堪萨斯城的店主和商人
一起吃午饭…
...and lunched with Kansas City
shopkeepers and merchants...
…自称是牧人或者投资商人…
...calling himself a cattleman
or a commodities investor...
…一个平易近人，有钱而又悠闲的人
...someone rich and leisured
who had the common touch.
他的胸口有两处未能痊愈的弹痕…
He had two incompletely healed
bullet holes in his chest...
…大腿上也有一处
...and another in his thigh.
他左手中指少了两节…
He was missing the nub
of his left middle finger...
…对此他很是小心，唯恐被人看见
...and was cautious,
lest that mutilation be seen.
他还有一种称为“粒状眼睑”的症状…
He also had a condition that was
referred to as "granulated eyelids"...
…这使得他比常人更频繁的眨眼…
...and it caused him
to blink more than usual...
…好像在他看来
周围的人们让他有点难以接受
...as if he found creation
slightly more than he could accept.
他在的时候，房间似乎更加炎热
Rooms seemed hotter
when he was in them.
雨似乎下得更频繁
Rains fell straighter.
时间似乎过得更慢
Clocks slowed.
声音被放得更大
Sounds were amplified.
他认为自己是一个
在一场永无终结的内战中…
He considered himself
a Southern loyalist and guerrilla...
…忠于南方的游击队员
...in a Civil War that never ended.
对于他做过的抢劫案，以及被控诉的17起谋杀案
他毫不悔过
He regretted neither his robberies,
nor the 17 murders that he laid claim to.
在密苏里州的堪萨斯城
他又迎来了一个新的夏天
He had seen another summer under
in Kansas City, Missouri...
…1881年9月5日…
...and on September 5th
in the year 1881...
…他34岁
...he was 34 years old.
你只要…你只要把东西滑进这里
就这里，到你袖子里…
You just... You just slide them things
right in there, right in your sleeve...
…然后等准备好了，就甩出来
...and then, when you get ready,
you just shake it out.
像那样，看，甩出来
Like that, right there. You shake it out.
[蓝切地，密苏里州，1881年9月7日]
玛丽・托德・林肯，暴君的妻子
在月圆时发疯了
Mary Todd Lincoln, tyrant's wife, fall
into hysterics when the moon was full.
总统的手下会用干草绳把她捆起来…
President's men would tie her up
with hay-baling wire...
…以免她丈夫的耳朵被她咬掉
...keep her from ripping
her husband's ears off.
你从没听别人说过
杰弗逊・戴维斯的老婆的闲话吧？
（美国内战中南方联邦的总统）
You never heard word one about the wife of
the Confederacy's Jefferson Davis, did you?
- 没有
- 对，没有
- I didn't.
- No, you didn't.
她可是她丈夫的贤内助
He did his duty by her.
- 噢，天，忘了你是小孩子了
- 不，我听懂了，我听懂了
- Oh, my God, I'm speaking to children.
- No, I get it, I get it, I get it.
联邦总统明白妻子的需要
他用高超的技巧和礼节…
The president of the Confederacy discerned
his wife's needs and satisfied them...
…满足了她
...with the utmost skill
and the utmost courtesy.
- 查理，你喷得我满鞋子都是
- 对不起，对不起，杰西
- Charley, you spit all over my boot.
- Sorry. Sorry, sorry, Jesse.
- 这里，弄干净
- 我来擦…我会擦干净的
- Here, get it off.
- I'll wipe it... I'll wipe it off.
但亚伯拉罕・林肯也许让他老婆
去疯狂购物了
But Abraham Lincoln probably sent his wife
on a shopping expedition.
- 一场三幕的戏
- 花的是从我们这偷去的钱
- A three-act play.
- With money stole from us.
开饭！
Chow!
我看林肯家双方都有病
I think insanity run on both sides
of that Lincoln family.
你说的没错
You're right about that.
那河…你跳进去
The river... You jump in the river.
- 开饭！
- 别害羞，迪克
- Chow!
- Don't be shy now, Dick.
- 再来一块肉
- 你骗人多了以后…
- One more piece of meat.
- When you diddle a lot...
给他留了一块很好的培根肥肉
There's a good piece of bacon fat
in there for him.
打扰了
Excuse me.
我随便散步，没想到打扰你了
I see I've traipsed right on in
and interrupted you.
那么你是谁？
Who are you, then?
鲍勃・福特
Bob Ford.
查理的弟弟？
Charley's brother?
对
Yeah.
我刚才说谎了，我不是偶尔路过
I was lying when I said
I just happened down here.
我在找你
我一开始没说实话，是不是很让人讨厌
I've been looking for you. I feel lousy
I didn't say so at the outset.
因为我给人的第一印象常常很不好…
Folks take me for a nincompoop...
…别人都当我是傻子
但我觉得自己…
...on account of the shabby first impression
I make, whereas I think of myself...
…只比詹姆斯兄弟差一点
...as being just a rung down
from the James brothers.
我希望如果我避开那些啄木鸟来见你…
I was hoping if I ran into you
aside from those peckerwoods...
…我就能向你展示我的特别之处
...I could show you how special I am.
我坚信我注定要干一番大事业的，詹姆斯先生
I honestly believe I'm destined
for great things, Mr. James.
我的特别之处一开始并不引人注目
I got qualities that don't come shining
through right at the outset.
给我一个机会，我能把活干好
我向你保证
You give me a chance, I'll get
the job done. I guarantee you that.
嗨，迪克，听说你骗了个印第安女人？
Hey, Dick, is it true you diddled a squaw?
快点，告诉我
我一直想睡一个红皮肤女人
（红皮肤：对印第安人的侮辱称呼）
Come on, you can tell me. I've always
wanted to lay down with a redskin.
这个，查理…
Well, Charley...
…你会有这样一种感觉…
...there's a feeling that comes over you...
…这个女人的手割下了一个教士的头皮
而你进入了她的身体…
...getting inside a woman whose hands
has scalped a congregation.
她们的阴道里有雷鸣般的声音…
There's this thunderous sound
that comes from their cooch...
…因为她们站着生孩子…
...on account of the fact that
they birth a child standing upright...
- …像野兽那样
- 什么样的声音？
...like a wild animal.
- What's it sound like?
雷鸣般的阴道是啥样就是啥样，查理
我不知道
Whatever a thunderous cooch sounds like
there, Charley. I don't know.
不对
No.
她们的阴道很吵，是因为…
They got a noisy quim
on account of the fact that...
…她们在平原上穿行的时候用它来装杂货
...they use their cunnis as a saddlebag
to carry sundries across the plains.
少来了，到底什么感觉？爽吗？
Come on, what'd it really feel like?
Did it feel good?
快点坦白，快
Come on, fess up, now.
我喜欢你，查理
I like you, Charley.
我也喜欢你，查理
I like you too, Charley.
这个…
Well...
你并不特别，福特先生
You're not so special, Mr. Ford.
你就像其他那些新手一样
自我吹嘘，想得到一显身手的机会
You're just like any other tyro
who's prinked himself up for an escapade.
希望成为那些江湖小说里面的神枪手
Hoping to be a gunslinger
like them nickel books are about.
你可以歇歇了…
You may as well quench your mind of it...
…因为你不是那块料，孩子
...because you don't have
the ingredients, son.
很遗憾，我的话影响了你的判断…
Well, I'm sorry to hear
you feel that way...
…让你这么看我
...as I put such stock
in your opinions.
作为一个枪手
我只有一把古董级的左轮手枪…
As for me being a gunslinger, I've just got
this one granddaddy Paterson Colt...
…还借了一条皮带来固定它
...and a borrowed belt to stick it in.
但我也的确有雄心壮志
But I also got an appetite
for greater things.
我希望借着加入你们的机会
能让自己离目标更近一步
I hoped by joining up with you, it'd put me
that much closer to getting them.
哎，让我怎么说好呢？
Well, what am I supposed to say to that?
今晚我当你的拍档
Let me be your sidekick tonight.
拍档？
Sidekick?
这样你能看到我的不足和闪光点
So you can examine my grit
and intelligence.
我不知道你这人到底怎样…
I don't know what it is about you...
…但你说的越多，就越让我感到不安
...but the more you talk,
the more you give me the willies.
我想我今晚不想看到你，好吗？
Now, I don't believe I want you anywhere
within earshot this evening, okay?
明白吗？
You understand?
- 我很遗憾…
- 你怎么还不走？快点
- Well, I'm sorry...
- Why don't you just get now? Scat.
好吧
All right.
我曾经和一个女孩在一起，她不是印第安人
I was with a girl once, wasn't a squaw.
但她很漂亮
But she was pretty.
她金黄的头发就像…
She had yellow hair like a...
噢，就是像什么东西
Oh, like something.
像一缕灿烂的阳光？
Like hair bobbed from a ray of sunlight?
对，对，就像那样
Yeah. Yeah, like that.
哥们，你…你说话真好听
Boy, you... You talk good.
华丽的词藻能表达感情
You can hide things in vocabulary.
也许你能帮我给她写个纸条，寄过去？
Maybe you and me could write her a note,
send it by post?
跟你说吧，艾德，你要做的…
See, all you gotta do, Ed...
…就是琢磨她的心思，然后一举搞定
...is predict her needs
and beat her to the punch.
嗯，这个女孩，她的工作真的很特别
Well, this girl, she has a real specific job.
- 特别？
- 我们只在一起过一次
- Specific?
- We was only together once.
她…
She...
她怕闪电，她从马车下面…
She was afraid of lightning,
and she came up under the wagon and...
…向上抱住了我
...just cuddled right up to me.
她也给了我很优惠的价格
She give me a kind price too.
嗯，的确很特别
Well, I'll be. That is specific.
嗯，当然，她也跟别人在一起过…
Yeah, sure,
she'd been with other people...
…但她对我说的那些话…
...but the kind of things she said to me...
…显然是真情流露
...people just don't say
unless they really mean it.
我的爱人说她只会嫁给我
My love said she would marry only me
即使朱庇特也不能让她动心
（朱庇特：罗马最高神）
And Jove himself could not make her care.
对于女人说给爱人的话，我想你也同意
For what women say to lovers, you'll agree
就像写在流水里，写在空气里
One writes on running water or on air.
老天，真不错，那我们就这么写给她
My God, that's good.
Let's write her that.
不行
No.
跟妓女说这些诗情画意的话没用
Poetry don't work on whores.
你好吗？
How do you do?
现在祝你生日快乐是不是太迟了？
Am I too late
to wish you a happy birthday?
你怎么知道我的生日？
How'd you know?
你要是知道我对你的了解程度，会很惊讶
You'd be surprised
at what I got stored away.
我是詹姆斯小伙方面的权威
I'm an authority on the James boys.
是吗？
Is you?
嗯…我刚刚和你哥哥弗兰克
友好的交谈了一会儿
Well... Well, your brother Frank and I,
we just had a real nice visit.
就是随便聊聊，在那边
Just chit-chatting about this and that,
right over there.
大概聊了一百个话题…
And must've been a hundred subjects
entertained...
老天，你知道这炖汤应该配什么吗？
Good Lord, you know
what this stew needs?
饺子？
Dumplings?
面条
Noodles.
来一碗炖汤面，你一晚上都会回味
You eat yourself some noodle stew
and your clock'll tick all night.
你见过费耶德市的那个女人吗？
她用鼻孔吸面条吃
You ever see that woman up in Fayette?
Suck noodles up her nose.
- 在费耶德？
- 我想我没见过
- In Fayette?
- I don't believe I have.
你没听说过她，嗯？
You never heard of her, huh?
那里有你想象不到的好事
You got canals up there
you never dreamed of.
有些话我不喜欢反复说…
I don't like to harp on a subject...
我不关心谁跟我一起做事，从不关心
I don't care who comes with me.
Never have.
所以大家都觉得我很合群
That's why they call me gregarious.
我听说你和这个戴礼帽的小伙子
谈得很不错
I hear you and young Stovepipe here
had a real nice visit.
你们还有一大片木头要砍呢，小子
Your boys have got about a acre
of lumber to haul, dingus.
你最好赶紧赶他们干活去
You better goose them down yonder.
1867年至1881年间
詹姆斯一伙犯下了超过25起…
The James Gang committed over 25 bank,
train and stagecoach robberies...
…在银行、火车和公共马车上的抢劫案
...from 1867 to 1881.
但除了弗兰克・詹姆斯和杰西・詹姆斯…
But except for Frank and Jesse James...
…其余所有初期成员
现在不是已死就是已经入狱
...all the original members
were now either dead or in prison.
我的眼睛、灵魂和我的身体
- Mine eye
All my soul and all my every part
这种罪恶，没有补救方法
And for this sin, there is no remedy
它已经深入我的心底
It is so grounded inward in my heart.
所以在蓝切地的最后一次抢劫行动中…
So for their last robbery at Blue Cut...
…兄弟俩从附近的山林里招募了一些…
...the brothers recruited a gang
of petty thieves and country rubes...
…小贼和乡下人
...culled from the local hillsides.
准点到达，动手！
Right on schedule, Buck!
灭了那些灯笼！
Snuff those lanterns!
看看那群傻子，他们肯定会互相绊倒
然后开枪把对方打成女人
Look at those fools. They're gonna trip
and shoot each other into females.
我打赌，他们要是这么做
我可以给他们找几百个女人
I bet you I could find them husbands
if they do.
散开！
Fan out!
别开枪！
Hold your fire!
- 注意他！
- 下去
- Watch him!
- Going down.
别开枪，你们这些白痴！
Hold your fire, you idiots!
别开枪！
Hold your fire!
让我进去
Let me in.
动手！小伙子们！
Buck! Boys!
动手，这边！
Buck, this way!
你觉得这锁撑得住吗？
Do you think that lock will hold?
不觉得
No, I don't.
快走，快走
Let's go, let's go.
你们别装聪明，也别逞强
Let's not get clever, nor courageous,
any of you.
你好啊，小伙子！
这些都是给我的？
Hey there, boys!
These are all for me?
看起来像是圣诞节的早晨
Looks like Christmas morning in here.
你好，朋友
Hey, friend.
我四处偷窥一下你不介意吧？
You mind if I have a peek around?
垃圾，不行
This shit. Nope.
不行
Nope.
你这里有什么好东西吗？
You got anything good here?
也许有
It could be.
保险箱打开！
Open that safe.
快点！
Do it!
- 你没必要砸他头啊
- 不，有必要，要不他们不服
- You didn't have to bop him.
- Yeah, he did. They needed convincing.
他们有他们的规矩，我有我的办法…
They got their company rules,
I got my mean streak...
…这就是我们干活的方式
...and that's how
we get things done around here.
- 过来看着他
- 快点，过去
- Get on over here and attend to this thing.
- Come on, go.
别开枪，一群白痴！
Hold your fire, you idiots!
再往里翻翻
Dig deeper.
快点！给我钱
- Come on!
- Give me your money.
- 还有你，站起来
- 让我看看你的手
- And you, stand up.
- Let's see your hands.
你有什么？
What have you got?
说英语
Speak English.
钱，钱，你听得懂吗？
Money. Money. You understand that?
给我钱！
Give me your money!
有一些收据
There's some receipts.
有一些五块的钞票
I got fives.
杰西，杰西
Jesse. Jesse.
看起来没啥东西
Don't look good.
这里没有十万美金，迪克
There ain't no 100,000 dollars
in here, Dick.
跪下
Get down on your knees.
为什么？
Why?
噢，你得开始祈祷了
Well, you ought to pray.
因为我要杀了你
I'm gonna kill you.
跪下！
Get at!
那你得强迫我了
You're gonna have to make me.
好吧
All right.
别杀他！不要，别杀他
Don't shoot him! No, don't shoot him.
轮不到你指挥我，艾德
Don't tell me what I can
and cannot do, Ed.
集合！
Round them up!
芝加哥报业在蓝切地的火车抢劫案上大做文章…
Chicago newspaper publishers made
a great deal of the Blue Cut train robbery...
…声称除了密苏里之外，没有一个州…
...alleging that in no state
but Missouri...
…会纵容詹姆斯兄弟达12年之久
...would the James brothers be tolerated
for 12 years.
嗨
Hey.
你嘴巴紧吗？
Can you keep a secret?
那要看你告诉我什么了
It depends on what you're concealing.
你害怕黑暗吗？
You afraid of the dark?
不
No.
你迷信吗？
You superstitious?
我放了…我放了一颗橡子在窗户上
来躲避闪电
I put... I put an acorn in the window
to keep the lightning out.
孩子，你走路跟猫一样没声音
Kid, you must've crept up on cat's paws.
我打赌，这是你第一次，也是最后一次
被人突袭的机会
I'll wager that's the first and last time
you'll ever be caught off-guard.
你几岁了？
How old are you?
二十
Twenty.
不过，我想，要到一月份…
Except, well, I guess I won't
really be 20 till...
我才20岁，所以…
Till January, so...
我19岁
I'm 19.
嗯，不过你是不是觉得自己
比实际年龄要老？
Yeah, you feel older than that, though,
don't you?
是的，会觉得
Yeah, I do.
嗨，弗兰克，你…你看
警方会不会已经出动了？
Hey, Frank, you...
You think the sheriff's out already?
- 相当有可能
- 是啊
- More than likely.
- Yeah.
今晚很顺利
I had a real fine time tonight.
- 是吗？
- 嗯，是的
- You think so?
- Yup. Yeah.
嗨，我不只是在吹嘘我和我弟弟
Hey, I wasn't just flapping my lips
about my kid brother and me.
我想说的是，如果你和杰西
能看清我们的胆识和勇气…
What I figured was if you and Jesse could
gauge our courage and our daring...
…你就该把我们收做固定搭档
...you might just make us
your regular sidekicks.
你们的勇气和胆识
Your courage and your daring.
关于搭档我听得够多了
你这口气跟你那该死的弟弟一样
I about heard all I want to about sidekicks.
You sound like your damn brother.
哦，跟你直说吧
是我弟弟让我来跟你说这些的，他…
Yeah. Well, I'll be square with you,
it's Bob who put me up to it. He's...
他有本事加入詹姆斯兄弟的队伍
但我却完全做不好
He's got plans for the James boys
I can't even get the hang of.
- 这活太复杂了
- 是吗？
- They're that complicated.
- Yeah?
嗯，你们可以打消这个念头了
Well, you can just
get shed of that idea.
因为今晚之后，我们就要金盆洗手了
Because after tonight,
there'll be no more shenanigans.
你可以在日记上记下来
You can jot that down in your little diary.
1881年9月7日，詹姆斯一伙
在蓝切地抢劫了最后一辆火车…
September 7th, 1881, the James Gang
robbed one last train at Blue Cut...
…从此弃恶从善
...and gave up their nightriding for good.
等等
Wait.
那么，你以后准备靠什么吃饭？
Well, how are you gonna
make your living?
也许我会去卖鞋
Maybe I'll sell shoes.
真不敢想象，早上起来…
I can't believe I woke up this morning...
…我还在想父亲是否会借我大衣穿…
...wondering if my daddy
would loan me his overcoat...
…而现在才过午夜…
...and here it is just past midnight...
…我已经抢了一列火车，坐在摇椅上…
...l've already robbed a railroad train
and I'm sitting in a rocking chair...
…和独一无二的杰西・詹姆斯聊天了
...chatting with none other
than Jesse James.
是啊，世界真奇妙
Yeah, it's a wonderful world.
这是什么？
What's this?
哦，对了
Oh, yeah.
今天早上我真的很激动
我在想是否能认出你或者弗兰克…
I was real agitated this morning, so I was
wondering if I would know you or Frank...
…分清楚你俩谁是谁
所以我带了这块描述你们的剪报
...tell you all apart, and so I had
this clipping that described you both.
想听听吗？
Want me to read it?
念吧
Go on.
嗯…我找一下，等等
Well... I gotta find it. Hold on.
在这里，找到了
Here. Here.
“杰西・詹姆斯，家里最小的孩子
一张脸像小姑娘一样，光滑又无辜
"Jesse James, the youngest, has a face
as smooth and innocent as a schoolgirl.
蓝色的眼睛清澈而又明锐
而且总是十分警觉
The blue eyes, very clear and penetrating,
are never at rest.
他外表高大，举止得体，善于忍耐…
His form is tall and graceful
and capable of great endurance...
…和进取
...and great effort.
杰西快乐而鲁莽，随遇而安
Jesse is lighthearted, reckless,
and devil-may-care.
- 他嘴上总是挂着一丝微笑…”
- 够了，够了，够了
- There's always a smile on his lips..."
- All right, all right, all right.
嗯，然后是…弗兰克，弗兰克，弗兰克
然后没了，然后…
Well, yeah, then it just... Frank, Frank,
Frank. That's nothing. And then...
你知道我床边放着什么吗？
You know what I got
right next to my bed?
是《火车劫匪》，或者是R・W・史蒂文斯写的
《詹姆斯家小伙子的故事》
Is The Train Robbers, or, A Story
of the James Boys by R.W. Stevens.
我是说，多少个夜里
在空无一人的图书馆…
I mean, many's the night I stayed up...
…我两眼通红，张着嘴巴…
...with my eyes open
and my mouth open...
…读着你们的故事
...just reading about your escapades
in the Wide Awake Library.
那些都是扯蛋，你应该知道
They're all lies, you know.
是，当然是
Yeah, of course they are.
如果觉得难受就没必要一直抽烟
You don't have to keep smoking that
if it's making you bungey.
亚历山大・富兰克林・詹姆斯
听说杰西・詹姆斯被暗杀的时候…
…应该人在巴尔的摩市
Alexander Franklin James
would be in Baltimore...
...when he would read of
the assassination of Jesse James.
因为他觉得弟弟性情古怪，喜怒无常
所以离开了他
He had spurned his younger brother
for being peculiar and temperamental.
但如果感觉到自己再也不会见到杰西…
But once he perceived
that he would never see Jesse again...
…弗兰克应该会感到
着急，丧气，不知所措
...Frank would be wrought-up,
perplexed, despondent.
我哥哥已经不和我谈那档子事了
My brother and me are hardly
on speaking terms these days.
嗯，我也没打算说
Well, I wasn't gonna mention it.
你怕了吗？
Are you scared?
没有，只是有点惊讶
No, I'm just surprised a little.
它的肉不是我喜欢的那种多汁的
They ain't as succulent as I like,
the devil to clean...
…但如果剥了皮，用大蒜和油来烤…
...but if a man skins them
and fries them in garlic and oil...
…老天，那是相当好吃
...mercy, them's good eating.
这个，我还没饿到那个地步
Well, I never been that hungry.
我给它们取了名字
I give them names.
比如说？
Such as?
比如敌人
Such as enemies.
我给它们取了敌人的名字
I give them names of enemies.
告诉伍德和查理准备好行李
Go tell Wood and Charley
to get their gatherings together.
好的
All right.
我也是吗？
Me too?
你可以留下
You can stay.
好吧
All right.
嗨
Hey.
- 你想要什么，啄木鸟？
- 没什么
- What do you want, peckerwood?
- Nothing.
只是杰西让我叫你俩收拾好东西…
Except to say Jesse wants
you two to gather your parts...
…然后上马离开镇子
...get on your horses
and get out of town.
而我留下来
And me to stick around.
喔，我可是他的表弟…
Well, whoa, I'm his cousin...
…我告诉你
...l'll have you know.
我妈妈是他爸爸的妹妹
My mama's his daddy's sister.
他们就是这么告诉你的，伍德？
Is that how they described it to you,
Wood?
你说话最好注意点，小样
You better watch your tongue,
young sapling.
凭什么就该是我出去而不是你，小兔崽子？
Why is it me who's gotta rattle his hocks
out of town and not you, Bunny?
别激动，要我说…
Put your horns away.
If I know Jess...
…一定是有一些又脏又累的活…
...there's some real nasty
sad-suzie work's gotta be done...
…等着鲍勃这个呆子去干
...and Bob's the ninny that has to do it.
哦，是啊，肯定是这样，查理
Oh, yeah, I'm sure that's it, Charley.
你12个小时前才认识他
他甚至连你的名字都不知道
You only met him 12 hours ago.
He doesn't even know your name.
伍德！告诉你爸
我十月份会在肯塔基州
Wood! You tell your daddy
I'll be in Kentucky in October.
我们可以一起去打鸟
We can hunt some birds together.
好吧
All right.
那为什么是鲍勃留下来了？
So how come it's Bob who gets to stay?
鲍勃要把我的马具搬到
这条街前面的一座房子里去
Bob's gonna move my gear to a house
down the street.
看到没？
See?
- 我无所谓
- 嗯，好吧
- I don't mind.
- Yeah, well.
听起来像是冒险行动
Sounds like an adventure.
他们在夜间搬到了杜鲁斯特大道1017号…
They moved to 1017 Troost Avenue
at night...
…这样他们的邻居就不能看清他们
或是他们带来的东西
...so that the neighborhood couldn't get
a good look at them or their belongings.
之后鲍勃以为杰西会让他睡八个小时…
Then Bob thought Jesse
would give him eight hours' sleep...
…然后一大早让他走
...and a daydreaming goodbye.
但在托马斯・霍华德的房子里
住了两天之后…
But with a second day
in the Thomas Howard house...
…鲍勃觉得也许他永远都不会离开了…
...Bob thought he might never go...
…也许他会成为小男孩的好脾气表哥…
...but might be brought in
as a good-natured cousin to the boy...
…还有芝的好帮手
...and a gentleman helper to Zee.
杰西到哪里他都跟着
He went everywhere with Jesse.
他们去了托皮卡交易所酒吧…
They made trips
to the Topeka Exchange Saloon...
…在那里杰西会花上60分钟
细品一杯啤酒…
...where Jesse could spend nearly
60 minutes sipping one glass of beer...
…并仍然抱怨感到醉意
...and still complain about feeling tipsy.
交谈时，鲍勃几乎不发表自己的看法
Bob would rarely vouchsafe his opinions
as they talked.
如果被问到，他通常会不安和微笑
If spoken to, he would fidget and grin.
如果杰西在和别人商谈
鲍勃会在一旁仔细观察他们的对话…
If Jesse palavered with another person,
Bob secretaried their dialogue...
…注意他声调的变化，每个手势
以及面部肌肉的抽搐…
...getting each inflection,
reading every gesture and tic...
…好像是在为一个逃犯撰写传记…
...as if he wanted to compose
a biography of the outlaw...
…又好像只在为模仿他做准备
...or as if he were preparing
an impersonation.
走开
Go away.
过去没人能悄悄靠近杰西・詹姆斯
Used to be couldn't no one sneak up
on Jesse James.
你觉得现在呢？
Now you think otherwise?
我也从没见过你不带枪
I ain't never seen you without your guns,
neither.
我想不通
I can't figure it out.
你是想变得像我…
Do you wanna be like me...
…还是想取代我？
...or do you wanna be me?
我只是开玩笑，没别的意思
I'm just making fun, is all.
第二天鲍勃就被热忱的送走了…
Bob was sent away cordially
the next day...
…杰西向他告了别…
...with a goodbye from Jesse...
…但芝却没有礼节性的同他告别
...but nothing from Zee
beyond what good manners demanded.
从堪萨斯市到他姐姐的农场有40里地
It was 40 miles to his sister's farm
from Kansas City.
他到那儿时已经接近傍晚了
And it was well into the afternoon
by the time he arrived there.
玛莎・博尔顿太太在1897年成为寡妇之后…
Mrs. Martha Bolton rented
the Harbison farm in 1879...
…就出租了她的哈比森农场
...just after becoming a widow.
靠着出租房间和提供饮食，她收入颇丰
And she made a good income
by giving rooms and meals...
…住户包括他的弟弟查理，威尔伯和鲍勃
还有詹姆斯一伙…
...to her brothers Charley, Wilbur and Bob,
and to members of the James Gang...
…他们在需要躲避风头的时候就会来这里
...who would appear
whenever they needed seclusion.
迪克！你会把她弄出毛病的！
Dick! You're gonna make her sick!
你要是不小心她会吐的！
She's gonna upchuck
if you don't watch out!
伍德・海特追求玛莎被拒绝…
Wood Hite had been spurned by Martha
in his affections...
…而他转而追求她女儿的企图…
...and his attempt to switch his pursuit
to her daughter...
…也因迪克・利都而遭到挫败
...was being thwarted by Dick Liddil.
等等，你得向我保证你没那么难缠
Wait a second, you assured me
that you were not ticklish.
你好！
Howdy!
这是怎么回事？怎么回事…？
What's going on, now?
What's going on...?
- 你好！
- 你是在撒谎吗？
- Howdy!
- Were you fibbing about that?
- 不是
- 完全不是
- No.
- Not at all.
你不该偷看的，迪克
You're not supposed to peek, Dick.
是啊，不过你这么漂亮
我真的无法把持
Well, you're just so pretty
I can't help myself.
- 这事你得警告他
- 你们好
- You need to be warning him about that.
- Howdy.
应该关心的是地里的庄稼
也应该关心关心工作…
Worry about the field instead,
might be able to worry about the work...
你们好！
Howdy!
- 终于到家了
- 我很高兴，鲍勃
- Finally home.
- I'm so glad, Bob.
我也住那个房间，鲍勃
别把我的东西弄乱了
I'm in that room too, Bob.
Don't mess with my things.
好的，爷爷
All right, Grandpa.
“7月9日
勤奋，机智，强烈的责任感…
"July 9th. Diligence, tact,
and a keen sense of responsibility...
…细致入微，这些都是你的强项
你很敬业”
...capacity for detail are your dominant
traits. Your sense of duty's strong."
你在这多久了？
How long you been there?
刚来，错过了很多好看的东西吗？
Just now arrived. Did I miss much?
如果你从没见过一个肮脏的男人洗澡
那么是的
Not unless you never seen a man
wash his dirty carcass before.
小伙子，你个子不大，嘴巴倒挺能说
Boy, you got a big old pecker
for being such a little squirrel.
你来这里看什么，迪克？
That what you come here to see, Dick?
没什么
No.
你哥哥说杰西在堪萨斯城多留了你几天
Your brother said that Jesse
kept you in Kansas City some extra days.
为什么？
What was the reason?
这个，我恐怕不方便细说
Well, I'm not at liberty to say exactly.
那我这么问你吧
杰西有提到我和康明斯在一起谋事吗？
Let me ask you this. Did Jesse mention
that me and Cummins were in cahoots?
有这回事？
Is that so?
哦，亲爱的，我说漏嘴了，是吧？
Oh, dear. I went on and said too much,
have I?
那么，还有谁跟你们一伙的？
Well, who else is partners with you two?
听着，要是被他知道，他会割断我们的喉咙
你不像我这么了解他
See, he'll cut our throats if he finds out.
You don't know him like I do.
谁要是跟着杰西干那些见不得人的事
然后又背着他密谋别的勾当…
You do Jesse dirt,
you connive behind his back...
…孩子，会被他带着镰刀追杀的
...boy, he'll come after you
with a cleaver.
那你们俩在密谋什么呢？
So, what are you two cahoots
cooking up?
不知道我该说不该说
Don't know that I should say.
我可不会花言巧语
骗你说出你那肮脏的小秘密
I'm not gonna wheedle
the dang news from you.
不如我们让它成为一个谜…
How about we'll leave it a mystery...
…这样我们都不会为这次谈话后悔？
...and then we won't neither one of us
regret our little chat?
能把那把转轮枪给我看看吗，鲍勃？
Can you hand me that six-gun there, Bob?
如果你胆敢跟杰西提起我的事…
If you so much as mention my name
to Jesse...
…孩子，我会知道的
...boy, I'll find out about it.
你最好相信我
You had better believe that.
然后我会找到你
And I'll look you up.
敲开你的门，暴跳如雷
I'll knock on your door,
and I will be as mad as a hornet.
我会毫不留情
I will be hot.
注意点手上的家伙，迪克
You be careful with that iron, Dick.
你知道我在这些问题上的立场
事情就这么简单
You know where I stand on these matters
and that's all there is to it.
我们从此以后还是亲密无间
Me and you can be as friendly as pigs
from now on.
我是兔崽子・福特，把手举起来！
I'm Bunny Ford, stick your hands
up in the air!
先生
Mister.
噢，你们胆子还不小啊
Oh, you have some nerve.
我们刚在看
詹姆斯小伙子们和墨西哥人的故事
We were just reading about the James boys
among the Mexicans.
这是谁？这不是杰西
What's this? This ain't Jesse.
- 你怎么知道
- 他不可能没有胡子
- You don't know that.
- He would've never wore no mustache.
他也不可能摸过大炮
Never was anywheres near a cannon.
让我看看这张
Let me see that picture.
孩子，我真不知道我在看什么
Boy, I can't even calculate
what I'm looking at.
- 给我
- 他从小时候起…
- Give me that.
- Ever since he was a child...
…就开始收集
任何和詹姆斯兄弟有关的东西
...Bob's collected whatsoever he could find
about the James brothers.
是啊，在房间里都搞了一个小博物馆
Yeah, got himself a little museum
in his room.
下次你再来偷看，最好随身带把枪防身！
Next time you come snooping around,
you better strap on a shooting iron!
喔，看我多害怕
Well, you can see how scared I am.
你也是，伍德・海特
再惹我，就一枪崩了你！
You too, Wood Hite. Cross me again,
I'll put a bullet through your head!
孩子，你…
Boy, you...
小子，你最好想想我表哥是谁…
Son, you better recollect
who my cousin is...
…你也许忘了
杰西就像珍惜圣经一样疼我
...because you've seemed to misremembered
that Jesse loves me like the Good Book.
现在，你可以装成一个
杂货店里的危险人物…
Now, you may play it like you're
a dangerous person in the grocery store...
…但别忘了，如果你伤害了我的感情…
...but don't misremember
who you be accounting to...
…你将面对的是谁
- 我才不管！
...if I so much get my feelings hurt.
- I don't care!
是不是要我喊，“嘿哟”
Do I have to yell "suwee"?
我们为何不先和好一阵子呢？
Why don't we make up,
be pleasant for once?
快快乐乐的度过这个晚上，不好么？
Why don't we pass the evening
like pleasant human beings?
衣服不错，牛仔
I like your nickel suit, cowboy.
看到什么了吗？
You see something?
一只鸟而已
Just a bird.
十月到来了…
The month of October came...
…杰西开始发现
私家侦探装扮成售货员…
...and Jesse began seeing
Pinkerton operatives in every floor walker...
…扫路工和普通人在一家店里打探消息
...street sweeper, and common man
poking about in a store.
11号的早晨，他叫醒妻子…
On the morning of the 11 th,
he would wake his wife...
…就像圣经里，圣家逃往埃及一样
...with the Scripture pertaining to
the Holy Family's flight into Egypt.
一夜间，托马斯・霍华德一家
就从堪萨斯市消失了
Overnight, the Thomas Howard clan
vanished from Kansas City.
之后不久，蓝切地劫车案中的四个人…
Shortly thereafter,
four of the Blue Cut train robbers...
…在格兰代尔附近的一间木屋里被捕
...were arrested in shacks near Glendale.
杰西是如何预先知道的，至今还是个迷
How Jesse could have known
remains a mystery.
他们居无定所
Theirs was a wandering existence.
选择了犯罪这条路…
Men who choose to be outlaws...
…就不能在一个地方呆上太久
...cannot afford to remain in one place
for very long.
- 喔，天哪，也许我要改变主意了
- 快走，快走
- Well, goodness. Maybe I'll change my mind.
- Let's go. Let's go. Let's go.
- 玛莎
- 忘了吧，哥们
- Martha.
- Buck up, man.
伍德和迪克
在跨越整个肯塔基州的途中都在斗嘴
Wood and Dick would bicker
across the entire state of Kentucky...
…一直到了罗斯威尔
伍德的父亲，也就是詹姆斯兄弟的叔叔…
...until they made Russellville, home
of Major George Hite, Wood's father...
…乔治・海特上校的家
...and uncle to Frank and Jesse James.
你离她远点
You stay away from this one.
他是我爸的妻子
She's my daddy's wife.
明白了吗？
You got it?
这菜是您做的吗，太太？
Did you cook this, ma'am?
我有个黑人女仆
I've got a nigger woman.
他说什么？
How's that?
迪克问菜是不是我做的
Dick asked if I cooked this.
是你做的吗？
Did you?
不是
No.
她嫁给他的时候知道他是这样的
She knew what he was like
when she married him.
看来我们都是夜猫子，你和我
I guess we're the night owls, you and I.
我很高兴
I'm glad.
怎么说？
How come?
你看起来挺有意思
You're interesting to look at.
你的性格让人感到很舒服
You have a real pleasant disposition.
我也说不清楚，似乎你让我感到全身温暖
And I don't know, you sort of
make me feel warm all over.
知道吗，别人都叫我…多情浪子
You know, I'm what they call a...
An inamorato.
嗯，我就知道你该有个外号
Well, I knew
there had to be a name for it.
如果伍德所说的片面之辞不假…
You and the Hites
don't get along too well...
…你和海特一家相处的不大好啊
...if I'm to trust Wood and his version
of the situation.
事实是，我们都恨透了对方
We hate each other like poison,
if you wanna know the truth.
如果我身上着火了
海特家族大部分人都会袖手旁观
Most of the Hites wouldn't spit on me
if I was on fire.
人们说，如果一个女人身上着了火…
They say that when a woman's on fire...
…你应该抱着她在地上打滚
并用身体罩住她
...you're supposed to roll her around on
the ground and cover her with your body.
哼，你欺负人
Well, you are a naughty tease.
不该睡觉了吗？
Isn't it about bedtime?
好的，我只是想亲吻一下这双娇小的手
Well, I'll just kiss those dainty nubbins.
晚安
Good night.
你有完没完？
Would you stop?
孩子，我想我咖啡喝多了
Boy, I believe I drank too much coffee.
受不了了，我要去趟厕所
I gotta go visit the privy
something terrible.
太难为情了
This is embarrassing.
你继续你的吧，我不介意
Now, you go ahead and do your duty.
I don't mind.
和一个陌生男人一起在厕所里
我可感到有些惊讶
I've sort of got stage fright with
a strange man in the commode with me.
为什么会陌生呢
I ain't strange.
我和其他男人的构造没什么区别
I'm built just like the rest of them.
你看起来美极了
You look awful pretty.
是吗？
Do I?
我这辈子还从没见过这么美的大腿
I haven't never in my life seen
such well-shaped limbs.
伍德还醒着么？
Is Wood awake?
这里只有我
It's just me.
希望你还能当我是个淑女
And I bet you thought I was a lady.
嗯，看上去你不大会收拾啊，对吧？
Well, you ain't much of a housekeeper,
are you?
你不是偶尔路过
You didn't just happen by.
为什么呢？
Why not?
过来休息一下吧
Go on and take a load off your feet.
你该讨个老婆了
You ought to get yourself a wife.
是啊
Yeah.
我想是的
I suppose.
我想问问玛莎，查理的姐姐
I was gonna ask Martha. Charley's sister.
我想问问她有没有这个意思
I was gonna ask her
if she could imagine it.
但估计伍德有他自己的打算
But I guess Wood has plans of his own.
而且迪克・利都还总是在中间插一腿
And there's always Dick Liddil
getting in the way.
但我还是会考虑一下
I'll give it some thought, though.
庄稼收成怎样？
Your crops come in?
没啥收获，只有一个小园子和一个牧场
No, I don't got much.
Just a garden patch and a pasture.
播种时我正好生病了
I was sick at planting time.
所以…
So...
艾德，你怎么了？
Ed, how you feeling now?
为什么这么问？
Why?
你举止有点古怪
You're acting queer.
是么，因为你我最近关系不是很好
Well, you and me ain't been
just real good friends lately.
这不是你的错，你心里明白
That's not your fault,
you understand that.
但你也听到传言了
You hear talk, though.
传言？
Talk?
别人谈论你
People tell you things.
你说来听听？
Why don't you give me an example?
吉姆・康明斯来过这里
Jim Cummins come by here.
吉姆・康明斯
Jim Cummins.
噢，吉姆说
Oh, and Jim says:
“你认识那些因为蓝切地案被捕的家伙？”
"You know them boys
that got caught in the Blue Cut deal?"
这个，吉姆说他听到谣言…
Well, Jim says he got word...
…说你准备杀了他们
...that you're planning to kill them.
我为什么要那么做？
Why would I do that?
也许只是谣言而已
That's just talk probably.
吉姆・康明斯，他还说了别的什么？
Jim Cummins. He say anything else?
没了，基本上，就这些
Nope. No, that was it, basically.
但我还是不明白你为什么害怕
That still don't explain why you're scared.
这个，因为你知道
我的处境也和他们一样
Well, I'm in the same situation, you see.
我看到你骑马过来的时候很害怕
I was terrified I saw you ride up.
- 我只是路过，艾德
- 但也许你听到传言了
- I just happened by, Ed.
- Suppose you heard gossip, though.
也许你听说吉姆・康明斯来过
也许你会想…
Suppose you heard Jim Cummins
come by, you might have thought...
…我们准备抓住你去领赏钱
没这回事
...that we were planning to capture you
or get that reward, and that ain't true.
但你有可能会怀疑
But you might have suspected it.
最近没听说什么闲言碎语
Haven't heard a lick of gossip lately.
我藏着六百块钱呢，我不需要政府的赏金
I got 600 dollars stashed away.
I don't need no governor's reward.
嗯，这也是原则问题
Well, it's the principle too.
那么…
Well...
- 很高兴路过这里
- 噢，我也是
- I'm glad I stopped by.
- Oh, me too.
我们一起出去骑马如何？
What do you say
if we were to go for a ride?
我们可以去镇上，我请你吃晚饭
We can go into town. I'll buy you dinner.
然后我走我的
Then I'll be on my way.
好的
Okay.
有空出去骑马吗？
You ready to go for a ride?
我们这是要去你那里吗？
We going to your place?
你最近有看到艾德・米勒吗？
You seen Ed Miller lately?
没人看到
Nobody has.
一定是去加州了
Must have gone off to California.
我想知道我们这是要去哪儿
I'd still like to know where we're going.
如果我们要去见吉姆・康明斯
你还打算去吗？
If you were going to see Jim Cummins,
wouldn't you follow this road?
我想会的
I guess so.
你好
Howdy.
噢，你是我爸爸的朋友吗？
Oh, are you friends of my pa's?
我们是吉姆・康明斯的朋友
We're friends of Jim Cummins.
这样，很不巧，他八月以后就不在了
Well, it so happens
he's been gone since August.
他也没说去哪儿了
And never said where he gone to.
- 我叫马特・柯林斯
- 艾伯特・福特
- I'm Matt Collins.
- Albert Ford.
很高兴认识你
Very happy to meet you.
- 迪克・杜尔宾
- 很高兴认识你
- Dick Turpin.
- Pleased to make your acquaintance.
我不知道他在哪里！放开我！
I don't know where he is!
Leave me alone!
闭嘴！闭嘴！
Shut your mouth!
You shut your mouth!
- 你给我闭嘴
- 我不知道他在哪儿！
- You shut your mouth.
- I don't know where he is!
- 我不知道！
- 给我进来
- I don't know!
- Get in there.
闭嘴
Shut up.
- 我不知道他在哪儿！
- 闭嘴
- I don't know where he is!
- Shut up.
- 我不知道！
- 闭嘴
- I don't know!
- Shut up.
- 老天
- 闭嘴
- Jesus.
- Shut up.
杰西，他只是个孩子
Jesse, he's just a kid.
他知道他的吉姆叔叔在哪里
这会让他很快变老
He knows where his uncle Jim is and
that's gonna make him old soon enough.
- 也许他真的不知道
- 他知道！
- Maybe he doesn't know.
- He knows!
有时候就是要多问几次
You need to ask and ask sometimes.
有时候小孩子一开始并不记得
但过一阵子就会想起来
Sometimes a child don't remember so much
at first. But it'll come back to him.
老天，快能撕下来了，宝贝
My goodness, she's about to rip off,
sweetie.
再用点力就能撕出口来了
Just a little more here to get her started.
然后我就能像撕一页书那样把它扯下来了
Then I think I can rip her off
like a page from a book.
老天，他都说不了话
Jesus, he can't even talk.
吉姆在哪里？
Where's Jim?
吉姆在哪里？吉姆在哪里？
Where's Jim? Where's Jim?
吉姆在哪里？吉姆在哪里？吉姆在哪里？
Where's Jim? Where's Jim? Where's Jim?
- 吉姆在哪里？
- 放手！
- Where's Jim?
- Quit it!
你个畜生！我不知道他在哪里！
You bastard! I don't know where he is!
你就是不相信我！
你连说话的机会都不给我！
You won't believe me!
You never even gave me a chance!
你把我…你把我嘴巴堵上了！
You kept my... You kept my mouth shut!
我从来不知道
吉姆在哪里或什么时候能回来！别烦我了
I never know where Jim is or
when he comes! So leave me alone.
放开我，你个狗娘养的！
Get off me, you son of a bitch!
我受够了
I'm worn out.
我不能，不能…
I can't. No, see...
反正我早已心乱如麻
My mind's all tangled anyway.
这种小勾当都会让我感到恶心
Little deals like this
just make me feel dirty.
你没事吧，杰西？
Are you all right, Jesse?
杰西病倒了…
Jesse was sick...
…感冒，疼痛，肺淤血
...with rheums, and aches
and lung congestions.
失眠使他眼窝严重发黑
Insomnia stained
his eye sockets like soot.
他从鸡那缠绕的肠道中…
He read auguries in
the snarled intestines of chickens...
…或者是猫毛在风中飘散的方向中
占卜未来
...or the blow of cat hair
released to the wind.
得到的都是凶兆，这让他感觉身陷囹圄
And the omens promised bad luck,
which moated and dungeoned him.
为什么这些活都是你干？
How come it's you
that's gotta do all the chores?
查理和鲍勃多给了些钱给玛莎
所以他们就不用做
Charley and Bob pay extry to Martha
so that they don't have to.
但还是不公平
It still don't seem fair.
玛莎
Martha.
噢，看看谁来了
Well, look what the cat dragged in.
你从肯塔基来的？
You come from Kentucky?
你怎么两耳不闻窗外事，玛莎？
Why do you have your head in a hole,
Martha?
伍德和迪克几个月前有过枪战
Wood and Dick had a shooting scrape
a few months ago.
去看着水壶，爱达
Cover the kettle, Ida.
你和迪克为什么那样？
And what did you and Dick
get in a scrape about?
我爸爸的老婆在煎猪排的时候…
Well, he tampered
with my daddy's wife...
…他却来和她调情…
...while a pork chop
burned on the skillet...
…所以我向他开枪
...so I shot at him.
爱达！
撇油脂的时候不要把大拇指伸进去！
Ida! Do not stick your thumb
in the cream when you skim it.
他的狡诈和沾花惹草的作风…
His chicanery and his philandering ways...
…是我们之间怨恨的导火索
...has instigated such malice.
他就像草丛中的黄蛇一样不可靠，玛莎
He's a yellow snake in the grass
and he can't be trusted, Martha.
但这事迪克的说法和你完全不同
Dick told me a complete other version
of that affray.
伍德・海特在楼下
Wood Hite's downstairs.
你说他来这儿了？
You mean he's here?
对，他昨晚很晚来的
Yeah, he come in late last night.
嗨，冷静点！
Hey, simmer down!
别上去惹事了，孩子们！早饭马上就好了
Don't get into a fracas up there, you boys!
I've got breakfast almost ready.
他还在吸气
He's still sucking air.
但我想他应该挂了
But I think he's a goner.
也许你们该上来祝他黄泉路上走好
Maybe y'all better come wish him well
on his journey.
伍德？
Wood?
你是个好伙计，伍德
You were a good fellow, Wood.
哦，希望你没受太多苦，伍德
Oh, I sure hope you're not
in frightful pain, Wood.
我想给你点水喝，但我怕你会噎着
I'd get you something to drink,
but I'm afraid you'd just choke on it.
小爱达会想你的
Little Ida's gonna miss you.
家里其他人也会的
So is the rest of the family.
嗯，这事算解决了
不过不能把他带到里士满去
Well, one thing's settled.
Can't take him into Richmond.
为什么？
Why not?
这个，一来，警察会把鲍勃抓进去
Well, one, sheriff'll put Bob in jail.
二来，要是杰西发现
他的表弟被杀死在我们这里…
And two, Jesse'll find out his cousin
Wood's been shot in our house...
…那我们就都完了
...and then that'll be the end
of each and every one of us.
“冷酷而又残暴得插了进来…
"And in one merciless, violent thrust
broke in...
…伴随着香水和啤酒…
...and carried all before him,
and scented and brewed...
…还有我处子之血的味道…
...reeking with blood of my virginity...
…在我的身体内膨胀到了极致”
...up to its utmost length in my body."
他并没有消失，让你失望了
He ain't disappeared,
if that's what you were hoping.
你在读哪一章？
What chapter you on?
她在直布罗陀遇到了一些阿尔及利亚海盗
She's met some Algerian corsair
down at Gibraltar.
这让她很兴奋
Got herself all agitated.
腿怎样了？
How's that leg?
痛得要死，鲍勃，谢谢你的关心
Full of torment, Bob. Thanks for asking.
虚心的人有福了…
Blessed are the poor in spirit...
…因为天国是他们的
...for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.
哀恸的人有福了，因为他们必得安慰
Blessed are them that mourn,
for they shall be comforted.
…的人有福了…
Blessed are the...
温柔
Meek.
温柔的人有福了
Blessed are the meek.
- 是他吗？
- 是的
- Is it him?
- Yeah.
他来这儿干嘛？
你觉得他知道伍德的事情吗？
Why is he here? Does he know
about Wood, do you think?
我不清楚，我只知道他不是很想念他
I don't know. All I know is
he don't miss very much.
- 如果他问到你，我该怎么回答？
- 告诉他我和马蒂在堪萨斯城
- What should I say about you if he asks?
- Tell him I'm in K.C. With Mattie.
他在猎杀野牛
能见到你们他真的很高兴
He was buffalo hunting.
He was thrilled to meet yours truly.
是啊，在欧洲，有两个美国人
人们肯定认得…
Yeah, over there in Europe there's only
two Americans they know for certain...
…马克・吐温和杰西・詹姆斯…
...Mark Twain and Jesse James.
- 怎么，是这个孩子
- 一切还好吗？
- Why, it's the kid.
- How's everything?
- 我从不摘下枪
- 是吗？
- I never take off my gun belts.
- Yeah?
好主意
Good thinking.
噢，查理，你脚受伤了？
Well, Charley, did you hurt your leg?
是啊，我滑…我从屋顶滑下去了…
Yeah, I slipped...
I slipped off the roof...
…像个傻子一样摔在了雪地上
...and I smacked down into a snow bank
like a ton of stupidness.
前一秒我还在惊叫，“噢，天哪”
One second I'm screaming,
"Whoa, Nelly!"
后一秒我已经被埋在齐脖深的雪地里了
Next second, poof,
I'm neck-deep in snow.
那么，是什么让你在大冬天爬上屋顶的？
Well, whatever possessed you
to climb a roof in December?
有一个…风筝
我说啥来着？有一只猫
There was a k... A kite. What am I saying?
There was a cat.
一只猫，在屋顶上，我去追它
A cat. It was on the roof
and I went after him.
是只公猫，在嗷嗷叫，我就摔了
It was a tomcat yowling
and what all, and I slipped.
我以为你畸形腿了呢
I thought maybe your club foot
was gaining on you.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
迪克去堪萨斯见他老婆去了
他之前在这呆过一阵子
Dick went to Kansas City to be
with his wife. He was here for a bit.
对了杰西，给你讲个可爱的故事吧
Hey, here's a cute story, Jess.
鲍勃11还是12岁的时候
Bobby was what, 11 or 12...
非常非常仰慕你
...and you were by far
his most admired personage.
不停地讲你
He couldn't get enough.
“杰西这样”、“杰西那样”
一天到晚说不倦
It was "Jesse this" and "Jesse that"
and "Jesse this" from sunrise to sunset.
真有趣
Fascinating.
还有更逗的呢
No, there's more. This is cute.
有次我们在吃饭，鲍勃问
“你们知道杰西穿几号鞋吗？”
We're at supper and Bob asks,
"You know what size boot Jesse wears?"
- 查理，杰西不想听这个
- 鲍勃别插嘴，让我说嘛
- Charley, Jesse doesn't wanna hear this.
- Shush, now, Bob, let me tell it.
鲍勃说，“你知道杰西穿几号鞋吗？”
Bob says... He says, "You know
what size boot Jesse wears?"
他说，“6寸半”，还说，“这够大吗？”
He says, "Six and a half." He says,
"Ain't that a big enough boot...
“他五尺八寸高呢”
...for a man 5'8"tall?"
我就想逗逗他，他是我小弟弟嘛
I decided to josh him a little, you know,
he being my kid brother and everything.
我就说，“因为他没有脚指头啊"
So I said, "He doesn't have toes is why."
这故事太傻了啊
That's a really stupid story.
“他有一次脚泡在水沟里，
趾头被鲶鱼啃没了”
"He was dangling his feet off a culvert
and a catfish nibbled his toes off."
鲍勃想破了头，就是想不明白
Bob taxed himself trying to picture it.
如果你觉得这故事好笑的话，
倒是个好笑话
That'd be a good joke if it was funny.
很逗吧，杰西？
Isn't that a cute story, Jess?
多给我讲讲吧，鲍勃
Give me some more conversations, Bob.
我想到了一个更牛的，是关于你…
I got one. This one's about as crackerjack...
It's the one about your...
让鲍勃讲吧
Let Bob tell it.
好吧
All right.
我都不知道你说什么
I don't even know
what you're talking about.
你不是说你和杰西有很多共同点嘛
About how you and Jesse
have so much in common.
来讲讲吧，鲍勃
Go on, Bob.
对啊，快，鲍勃
Yeah, come on, Bob.
给我们讲个故事
Tell us a story.
- 不要
- 快啦，让杰西高兴一下
- Nope. No.
- Come on, entertain Jesse. He's here.
说嘛
Come on.
说了你不要生气，我觉得
Well, if you'll pardon my saying so,
I guess...
我们俩有很多重叠的地方，挺有趣的
...it is interesting the many ways
you and I overlap and whatnot.
从我们的爸爸说起吧
I mean, you begin with our daddies.
你爸爸是个浸信会牧师
Your daddy was a pastor
at the New Hope Baptist Church...
而我爸爸是艾克塞尔西奥泉市的牧师
...and my daddy was a pastor
at the church in Excelsior Springs.
你是家里三个兄弟中最小的
我家五兄弟，我最小
You're the youngest of three James boys,
and I'm the youngest of five Ford boys.
查理和我中间还有一个哥哥，韦伯
Between Charley and me,
there's another brother, Wilbur...
他的名字是六个字母的
...with six letters in his name.
你和弗兰克中间有个哥哥叫罗伯特
名字也是六个字母的
And between Frank and you, is another
brother Robert, also with six letters.
恰好我的洗礼教名也是罗伯特
And my Christian name
is Robert, of course.
你眼睛是蓝的，我也是
You have blue eyes, I have blue eyes.
你五尺八寸高，我也是
You're 5'8"tall, I'm 5'8" tall.
我12岁的时候列出来一长串的相似点
比你睡衣还长呢
Me, I must have had a list as long as
your nightshirt when I was 12, but...
但是长大后这种好奇心了就没了
...I seem to have lost some curiosities
over the years.
他还真厉害
Ain't he something?
我有没有给你们讲过
有个叫乔治・谢坡德的家伙
Did I ever tell you the story about
that scalawag, George Shepherd?
他是考崔尔（内战时南方联盟游击队指挥官）
底下的一个官兵
Shepherd's one of
Quantrill's lieutenants.
我想起他是因为
他的故事和鲍勃有点像
He give me a story much like Bob's
what bring him to mind.
他给我讲
我们俩有多少多少相似点
Going on about how much
we had in common, and so on...
就想加入我们
...so he could get in the gang.
没想到他对我心怀怨恨
How could I have known
he had a grudge against me?
没想到他为了赢得我欢心，谎话连篇
How could I have known
he was lying to get on my good side?
我说，"乔治，加入我们吧，很高兴你入伙”
I said, "George, come on aboard.
Glad to have you."
乔治以为自己很聪明，但其实不然
George thought he was smart,
except he wasn't.
有天早上，乔治进来营地
One morning, George rides into camp...
就有二十来支枪指着他
...and about 20 guns open up on him.
乔治只有一只眼，
要阴杰西，得有两只眼
See, old George, he only had one eye. You
gotta have two eyes, you wanna get Jesse.
你不应该把我和乔治・谢坡德相提并论
You ought not think of me
like you do George Shepherd.
你让我想起了他
You brought him to mind.
这不是什么抬举我的话
Well, it's not very flattering.
饭做得真好吃，玛莎
Sure is good eating, Martha.
你喜欢就好
Well, I'm so glad you enjoyed it.
乔治为什么会对你心怀怨恨？
How come George
had a grudge against you?
我问你呢，乔治为什么会对你心怀怨恨？
I said, how come George
had a grudge against you?
乔治有个侄子
他想让我在内战时，保护他侄子
Well, you see, George had a nephew
he wanted me to protect during the war.
那人身上有5000美元
This nephew had 5000 dollars on him.
结果他被杀了，钱也被抢光
It just so happens he winds up killed
and someone swipes that money.
乔治蹲监狱的时候，有人偷偷告诉他
And when George is in prison,
someone whispers to him:
“是杰西・詹姆斯杀了那孩子的"
"It was Jesse James
slit the boy's throat."
只是些流言蜚语，是吧？
It was just mean gossip, was it?
鲍勃是这方面的专家，
我们请教他吧
Bob's the expert. Let's put it to him.
哦，天啊，我惹恼他了
Oh, dear, I made him cranky.
我没有生气，只是以前我经历过这种事
I'm not cranky. I just been
through this before is all.
周围的人都嘲笑我，没完没了
Most people get around on making fun
of me. They don't ever let up.
某人真够怕羞的
Someone's getting awful fresh over there.
女人，闭嘴行吗
Woman, shut your face for once.
我不想你溜回房间生闷气
Don't want you to skip off
to your room and pout...
你还不知道我为什么过来这边
...without knowing why I come by
for this visit.
为什么？想给我们道歉
Why? So you could
tell us how sorry you are...
因为你揍了我们的堂弟艾伯特一顿？
...you had to slap our cousin Albert around?
我过来
I come by...
是想问你们两兄弟
...to ask if one of you two Fords...
想不想和我一起上路
...would care to ride with me
in a journey or two.
我看我们都觉得应该选查理吧
I guess we both agree
it ought to be Charley.
你太急躁了点
You've been acting sort of testy.
你最近有没有见过伍德・海特？
Have you seen Wood Hite lately?
没有
No. Not at all.
这炖菜里肯定加了松鼠肉
I swear that stew
had some squirrel meat in it.
- 还在和他吵？
- 对
- Still arguing with you, is it?
- Yeah.
- 你是查尔斯・福特？
- 是的，太太
- You're Charles Ford?
- Yes, ma'am.
我们以前见过
You've seen me once or twice before.
我有封乔治・海特寄来的信
I got a letter from George Hite.
他找不到他儿子了
He hasn't seen hide nor hair of him.
你说你没见过伍德？
And you say you haven't seen Wood?
我想不出来他能去哪
No, l... I can't imagine where he could be.
是吗？
Yeah?
睡够了没？
You finished with your sleeping?
如果没什么事的话，我想多睡几个小时
I could use a couple more hours
if it's no trouble.
好吧
Yeah.
我内心一直很挣扎，不知道该不该告诉你
I been holding a discussion with myself
over if I ought to tell you this or no.
但最后我善良的一面赢了
My good side won out and...
我想把事情说清楚
Well, I wanna make a clean breast
of things.
可是我现在脑子还不太清楚
Yeah, my mind's a little cobwebby
is the only drawback.
我还想再…再睡一会
I could use a little...
A little more sleep.
你知道我去了肯德基州吧？
You know I went to Kentucky?
知道
Yeah.
我回来途经萨林县
I come back through Saline County and...
我想
...I think to myself:
“不如去看看艾德・米勒吧？”
"Why not stop by and see Ed Miller?"
我就去看了
So I do.
不过结果我不太满意
Well, things are not to my satisfaction.
艾德为了某些事，惶惶终日的
Ed's got himself all worked up
over something.
我看得出来，他在扯谎
I can see that he's lying like a rug.
我就对自己说，“适可而止吧”
So I say to myself, "Enough's enough."
我对艾德说，“艾德”
And I say to Ed, "Come on, Ed.
“咱们出去走走吧”
Let's go for a ride."
你明白我说什么吗？
You understand what I'm saying?
出去走走就是
Going for a ride is like...
出去走走就是给他苦头吃的意思？
Going for a ride
is like giving him what-for?
正是
Exactly.
那么…
So...
艾德和杰西…
...Ed and Jesse...
…在路上吵起来了
...they argue on the road.
你有没有数过星星？
Did you ever count the stars?
我每次数的都不一样，它们不停在变
I can't ever get the same number.
They keep changing on me.
我连星星到底是什么都不清楚
I don't even know what a star is exactly.
你的身体知道
Well, your body knows.
只是你的心忘记了
It's your mind that forgot.
你先走，我会追上你的
You go on ahead, partner.
I'll catch up with you.
没事
It's okay.
没事的，亲爱的，没事
It's okay, sweetheart. It's okay.
吵到紧要关头上
And when push came to shove...
杰西一枪把艾德给毙了
...Jesse shot and killed him.
杰西杀了他
Jesse did.
你猜对了
You got it.
你…
You...
你看
So, you see, your...
你堂弟，我没拿他怎么样
Your cousin, he got off easy.
只是跟他玩玩而已
I was just playing with Albert.
是啊，我有时候也弄得他直嚷嚷
Yeah, I made him squeal
once or twice myself.
只是没你那么彻底而已
I'm just not as thorough as you are.
作为交换，你有故事要告诉我吗？
You got a tale to swap with me now?
我不明白你意思
I don't get your meaning.
我觉得，如果你也有什么事情要坦白的话
Seems to me, if you have something
to confess in exchange...
那你最好
...it'd only be right...
现在就马上告诉我
...that you'd spit it out now.
我想不出有什么事情
I can't think of a single thing.
比如，伍德・海特？
About Wood Hite, for example.
我不会…我不都跟你说了
我不知道他去哪了
I'm not gonna... I been saying over and
over I can't figure out where he's gone.
我不能睁眼说瞎话啊
Now, I'm not gonna change my story
just to have something to spit.
- 那为什么你弟弟那么不安？
- 哪个弟弟？
- Why was your brother so agitated?
- Which?
鲍勃
Bob.
他一向都那样
That's just his way. He's antsy.
知道吧？
You know?
你继续睡觉吧
You go on back to sleep now.
你现在倒让我不安了
You got me agitated now, you see?
是啊，杰西在的时候，谁都安定不得
Yeah, just ain't no peace
when old Jesse's around.
我老婆真可怜
You ought to pity my poor wife.
艾德・米勒是我的好朋友
Ed Miller was a good friend of mine.
有一次打扑克的时候
他把我介绍给你的
He introduced me to you
at that one poker game.
你真那么想听实话的话
我就跟你说，我有点生你的气
I'm a little angry with you, if you
wanna know the God's honest truth.
你也该可怜一下我
You ought to pity me too.
为了证明和詹姆斯匪帮有联系
鲍勃告诉警方
As proof of his confederacy with
the James Gang, Bob told the authorities...
迪克・利都正在一家租来的农舍
...that Dick Liddil was sleeping over
at the rented farmhouse...
他的腿受伤了，在疗伤
...while his ruined leg mended.
还画了一幅哈比森庄园的地图
And then, created a map
of the Harbison property...
只是没画上
他们埋藏伍德・海特尸体的那条小溪
...leaving out the creek where
Wood Hite's remains now moldered.
你们被包围了！
Right, you boys are cornered!
乖乖地出来，就不会受伤！
Come on out peaceably
and nobody'll get shot up!
别开枪
Don't shoot!
快出来
Come on out and show yourself!
哈罗
Hello.
逮到他了
We got him.
克尔特手枪给我
Give me that Colt, son.
- 好了
- 安德鲁・詹姆斯・利都
- All right.
- Andrew James Liddil...
我有你的逮捕令
...I have a warrant here
for your arrest...
那个周日，2月19日
暴风雪席卷了密苏里州
Snowstorms would move over Missouri
that Sunday, February 19th...
使得商铺超过两天无法营业
...shutting down commerce
for more than two days.
- 走，走
- 文件在吗？
- Go, go, go.
- Are the papers here?
- 他想知道，文件在不在
- 我才不在乎他要什么
- He wanted to know if the papers are here.
- I don't care what he wants.
但这并没有阻止罗伯特・福特
Yet this wouldn't prevent Robert Ford...
去参加克里廷顿州长
...from presenting himself
to Governor Crittenden...
周三为克莱格步枪队举行的庆功晚会
并和州长会面
...at the Craig Rifles Ball on Wednesday.
趁着这个难得的机会
I deem it a great privilege
on this glorious occasion...
我想公开表扬
...to recognize publicly...
亨利・克莱格队长那机智迅速的行动
...the intelligent and effective assistance...
协助我和密苏里州
...that Captain Henry Craig has rendered
the state of Missouri and myself...
在杰克森县
...in our joint quest
to rid Jackson County...
消灭詹姆斯匪帮
...of the James band.
克莱格队长的任务
The task that Captain Craig
has assumed...
是需要无所畏惧，高度警惕
...will require fearless courage,
extraordinary vigilance...
方法适当，才能完成的
...and an unerring selection
of instrumentalities.
我妻子暗示我，话说到这里就够了
Well, I've gotten the signal from my wife
that enough is enough.
但是，最后我还想
However, before I sit...
希望大家和我一起
...I would like to ask you
to join me in a toast...
向这位密苏里州的儿子
...to a great son
of the state of Missouri...
- 我的朋友，亨利・克莱格祝酒
- 恭喜，恭喜
...my friend, Henry Craig.
- Here, here.
是啊
Yes.
告诉我的律师吧
Just let my attorney know.
那是谁？是谁？
Who is that? Who is it?
走开
Get out of the way now.
你惹的麻烦太多了
You know, you're more goddamn trouble
than you're worth, Bob.
我只是想打个招呼而已
I was just gonna say hello.
不行啊，鲍勃，所以把你带下来了
No, you weren't gonna do that, Bob.
That's not why you're down here.
你以为你自己是
在晚会上华丽亮相的美女吗？
You think it's your goddamn coming-out.
You think you're the belle of the ball.
上楼去，别暴露身份了，小混蛋
Now you get upstairs and try to keep your
identity secret, you silly little bastard.
到合适的时候，州长会见你的
带他上楼
The governor'll see you in good time.
Take him up, boys.
之后，鲍勃会被不停地盘问
Bob would later be cross-examined
repeatedly...
解释他和警方做的交易
...about the exact nature of the deal
he had made with the authorities.
但他的回答总是自相矛盾
And he was never consistent
in his recollections.
我妻子在隔壁房间睡着呢
尽量轻声说话
My wife's asleep in the other room,
so let's speak as quietly as we can.
你是迪克・利秃吧？
So you're Dick Little.
利都
Liddil.
什么？
I beg your pardon?
是d的音
I spell it with two D's.
他向我们全盘道出了
He's given us a full confession, governor.
报纸还没知道
Newspapers haven't caught onto it yet.
您向他保证，会给他特赦
And you've guaranteed him
a conditional pardon...
赦免他犯的所有抢劫罪
...and amnesty for all the robberies
he's committed.
你是罗伯特・福特？
You Robert Ford?
多大了？
How old are you?
二十
Twenty.
你也向汀布莱克警长投降了？
You surrender to Sheriff Timberlake
as well?
不是，他的哥哥查理・福特
才是詹姆斯匪帮的匪徒
No, no, governor. That's his brother,
Charley Ford, he's in the James Gang.
和小鲍勃没关系
But little Bob here,
we got nothing on Bob.
他只是充当一个
He's just acting in capacity as a...
秘密警探而已
...private detective.
杰西・詹姆斯上个月给我打了个电报
Jesse James sent me a telegram
last month...
说就算要拆了一整辆火车
他都要逮着我杀了我
...saying he'd kill me
if he had to wreck a train to do it.
他说要是我落到他手上
他会把我的心割下来
He said once I got in his hands,
he'd cut my heart out...
像熏肉那样撕了来吃
...and eat it in strips like it was bacon.
我会先拆掉他的火车
I'll wreck his train first.
抱歉，州长大人，我在想别的事情
I'm sorry, Your Excellency.
I was thinking about something else.
杰西・詹姆斯只是一个匪徒
Jesse James is nothing more
than a public outlaw...
打家劫舍，臭名远扬
...who made his reputation
by stealing whatever he wanted...
谁挡他的道就杀谁
...killing whoever got in his way.
有的傻瓜说他是在报复
共和党人和联邦政府人
You'll hear some fools say he's getting back
at Republicans and Union men...
因为内战时他的家人遭了不少罪
...for the wrongs his family suffered
during the war.
但他甚少根据政治立场挑选受害人
But his victims have scarcely been selected
with reference to their political views.
我跟你们说，他的罪孽很快会遭到报应
I'm saying his sins will soon find him out.
他造的孽也快到头了
I'm saying his cup of iniquity is full.
杰西・詹姆斯是个极端案件
I'm saying Jesse James
is a desperate case...
也需要极端的制裁
...and may require a desperate remedy.
那您就找对人了
Y'all got the right man for the job.
快走呀
Come on. Come on, now.
快走
Come on, now.
你有没有想过自杀？
Have you ever considered suicide?
没有吧，总是有想做的事
I can't say that I have. There's always
something else I wanted to do.
有时候事情有转机了
有时候我会换一个角度看问题
Or my predicaments changed,
or I saw my hardships from a different slant.
以后会发生什么事谁也不知道
自杀太不值得了
You know all what can happen.
It never seemed respectable.
告诉你吧，有一件事是肯定的
I'll tell you one thing that's for certain.
你窥见过死后世界之后
就不介意死掉了
You won't mind dying
once you've peeked over the other side.
你不会再想回到你的身体里
You'll no more wanna go back
to your body than...
就好像你不会想把自己的呕吐物
给吃回去一样
...you'd wanna spoon up your own puke.
嘿，我们计划抢银行的话
Hey, since we're looking to rob banks...
不如再加一个人
...I was wondering if we could
add another fella to the gang...
下次干活的时候好保着命呀
...and sort of see if we couldn't
come out of our next job alive.
鲍勃想知道，他下次能不能和我们
一起去打劫银行或者…
Bob wanted to know could he ride with us
next time we took on a savings bank or...
打劫银行或者…
A savings bank or a...
火车
A railroad.
鲍勃看起来虽然挺小的
Bob isn't much more than a boy
to most appearances.
但他资质还是挺好的
But there's about two tons
of sand in him.
必要时候，他会使枪
And he'll stand with a shooter
when that's what's called for.
他挺机灵的，心思挺细的
And he's smart too.
He's about as intricate as they come.
我见过这孩子，你忘了？
You forget I already met the kid.
他很仰慕你
Hell, he surely thinks highly of you.
所有美国人都仰慕我
All of America thinks highly of me.
但是，要找第三个人作帮手
Still, not like you got two million names
to snatch out of a sock...
也不是说随手拈来的吧？
...whenever you need a third man.
你在努力说服我
I can see you trying to
wear me down on this.
我就是这个意思
That's my main intention.
他们密谋
在内布拉斯加，科罗拉多和密苏里州
Robberies would be conceived
but never carried out...
进行抢劫，但都没有开始行动
...in Nebraska, Colorado and Missouri.
这时
During this time...
亨利・克雷格指示罗伯特・福特
回到伊莱亚在里士满的杂货店
...Henry Craig enjoined Robert Ford to return
to Elias' Grocery Store in Richmond...
并在那里等候
詹姆斯・汀伯莱克警长的指示
...and await instructions
from Sheriff James Timberlake.
好，三罐…
All right, three cans...
桃子，两罐
...peaches. Two cans...
两罐豌豆
Two cans sifted peas.
一瓶
One bottle...
玛丽牌精华露，半…
...Mary's Morning Tonic, and a half...
半袋面粉
Half a sack of flour.
马上回来
I'll be right with you.
我没见过他的任何踪迹
I haven't seen any sign of him.
你知道他住在哪里吗？
Well, do you know where he's living?
不知道
No.
不知道？
No?
我不知道他是怎么做到…
Well, I can't guess how he does it...
总是对一切了如指掌的
...but he is always knowledgeable
about what's going on.
他会知道我在这里见你
你该做好这个心理准备
He's gonna know I've been here with you.
You ought to take that for granted.
一有机会他就会把你杀掉
And he will kill you if he gets the chance.
你愿意冒这个险吗？
Are you willing to risk that?
愿意
Yes, I am.
我这辈子都那么不起眼
I've been a nobody all my life.
永远当我是个小孩
I was the baby.
答应我的事情也没实现过
I was the one they made promises to
that they never kept.
我记忆中
杰西・詹姆斯永远那么高大显赫
And ever since I can remember it,
Jesse James has been as big as a tree.
我准备好了，吉姆
I'm prepared for this, Jim...
我会完成任务的
...and I'm gonna accomplish it.
我知道这是我唯一的机会
I know I won't get
but this one opportunity...
我保证不会把这事毁了的
...and you can bet your life
I'm not gonna spoil it.
那么…
Well...
等待合适的时机
...wait for your chance.
别和他独处，还有千万…
Don't let yourself be found alone with him,
and do not...
不要让他到你身后
...let him get behind you.
你被选中了
You been chosen.
什么意思？
Well, what do you mean?
你哥哥说你想加入我们
Well, your brother said that
you might wanna join us.
不过，你对这杂货店的感情
也许比嘴上说的更深
But maybe you like this grocery store
more than you said you did.
- 想我了？
- 对啊
- So you missed me?
- Oh, yeah.
每晚想你想到哭
I been crying myself to sleep every night.
别让他看到我们俩
Don't let him see us so much as wink.
他现在多疑得跟个野狼似的，谁也不信
He's suspicious as a damn coyote,
and he don't trust you one iota.
- 那我想…
- 嘿
- Well, I guess that makes...
- Hey.
他已经干掉艾德・米勒了
还说得轻描淡写的
He already put away Ed Miller. He said so
like it was something piddly he'd done.
如果我们俩能单独待多过一分钟
我很想再跟你谈谈
If we're ever alone for more than a minute,
I'd like a chance to talk to you further.
他们给我十天时间
They gave me ten days.
干吗？
For what?
逮捕他
For arresting him.
你和我?
You and me, huh?
不是他动手就是我们动手
这事躲不过的
It's gonna happen one way or another,
Charley. It's gonna happen.
干嘛不趁这个机会捞点钱
So it might as well be us
who get rich on it.
- 鲍勃，他是我们的朋友
- 他杀了艾德・米勒
- Bob, he's our friend.
- He murdered Ed Miller.
一有机会，他就会去杀利都和康明斯
And he's gonna murder Liddil and Cummins
if the chance ever comes.
照我看来，杰西正一个个地
把帮里的兄弟做掉
It seems to me Jesse's riding from
man to man, saying goodbye to the gang.
你的友情会害死你的
So your friendship could put you
under the pansies.
我会认真考虑的，鲍勃
我现在只能到这一步了
I'll grind it fine in my mind, Bob. I can't
go any further than that right now.
你会想通的
You'll come around.
你认为这都是编造的，是吗？
You think it's all made up, don't you?
他的故事只是报纸编的
You think it's all yarns
and newspaper stories.
他也不过是个人
He's just a human being.
从今以后，你们俩不许离开我行动
From now on, you two
won't go anywhere without me.
从今以后，你们的行动要得到我批准！
要向我请示！
From now on, you'll ask for my permission!
From now on, you'll ask to be excused!
查理，把马带到马棚里
鲍勃，进屋去吧
Charley, take them horses
around the barn. Bob, you go on inside.
- 你好，玛丽
- 嗨
- Hello, Mary.
- Hi.
看我在堆肥里找到的萝卜(欧洲萝卜）
Look at this rotten parsnip
I found in the compost heap.
你没提过鲍勃会来
You never mentioned Bob would be here.
可能他想留作惊喜呢
Maybe he was saving it
as a pleasant surprise.
现在来了两位堂兄弟做伴了
Got two cousins for company now.
这么着…
How it's gonna be is...
我们下周一下午离开，到普拉特市
...we'll leave next Monday afternoon
and ride down to Platte City.
离堪萨斯市多远？
How far is that from Kansas City?
往南三十英里
Platte City's 30 miles south.
你，我和查理晚上在森林里睡一夜
You and me and Charley'll
sleep in the woods overnight...
我们会在关门之前一段时间
进攻富国银行
...and we'll strike the Wells Bank
sometime before the court recesses.
具体是几点？
What time will that be exactly?
这你没必要知道
Well, you don't need to know that.
我和你哥哥一起的时候很惬意
You know, I'm real comfortable
with your brother.
虽然他长得难看，身上也臭
Hell, he's ugly as sin,
he smells like a skunk...
还无知得要命
...and he's so ignorant
he couldn't drive nails in the snow...
但他很好相处
...but he's sort of easy to be around.
你就不一样了，鲍勃
I can't say the same for you, Bob.
你这么说让我很难过
Well, I'm sorry to hear you say that.
你知道那种情况吧
你和你爱人在月色之下
You know how it is when you're
with your girlfriend and the moon's out...
虽然她从没开口说
但你知道她等着你亲她
...and you know she wants to be kissed,
even though she never said so?
恩
Yeah.
你的种种迹象，让我很难过
Well, you're giving me signs
that grieve my soul...
让我觉得…
...and make me wonder...
可能你对我的看法已经变了
...maybe your mind's
been changed about me.
你要我怎么办？向天发誓？
Well, what do you want me to do?
Swear my good faith on the Bible?
你俩在吵架？
You two having a spat?
我正准备发火呢
I was getting ready to be angry.
坐过来点，孩子
Sit over here closer, kid.
过来过来
Come on.
查理，到时你看着马
Charley, you'll stay with the animals.
我和这孩子
Me and the kid...
会在中午之前走进那银行
...will walk into that bank
just before noon.
鲍勃会让那出纳员
Bob will move that cashier...
没法拿到柜台底下藏着的枪
...away from the shotgun
that's under the counter...
然后我就溜到那出纳员后头
...and I'll creep up behind that cashier...
这样把他的头朝后扳
...and I'll cock his head back like so.
我会说
And I'll say:
“象你这样的废柴怎么还活着
"How come an off-scouring
like you is still sucking air...
而我那么多手下就已经送命了呢？”
...when so many of mine
are in coffins?" I'll say:
“你怎么还能活到20岁？”
"How did you get to reach 20
without leaking out all over your clothes?"
如果我不喜欢他的态度
我会狠狠地割掉那小子的喉咙
And if I don't like his attitude,
I will slit that phildoodle so deep...
让他像条脱水的鱼一样乱跳
...he will flop on the floor like a fish.
天啊，发生什么了？
My God, what just happened?
鲍勃，我能听到你的小脑袋发动了
Boy, I could hear your gears grinding...
听到你在问自己
“天啊，下次他会干出什么事？”
...hear your little motor wondering,
"My gosh, what's next?
“我会怎么样？”
What's happening to me?"
看你这样子，鲍勃
You were precious to behold, Bob.
脸白得跟墙一样
You were white as spit in a cotton field.
你吓到他了
You got him. You got him.
你想知道这是什么感觉吗？不舒服
我真的不推荐你这么做
You wanna know how that feels?
Unpleasant. I honestly can't recommend it.
查理看来也被吓倒了
The old Charley looked stricken!
是啊，是啊
I was. I was.
“太恐怖了”，查理想道
“把我一天的心情都毁了”
"This is plumb unexpected," old Charley
was thinking. "That done ruined my day."
天呀
Hell. Hell.
那晚，杰西和鲍勃睡在孩子们的房间
Jesse slept with Bob
in the children's room that night.
鲍勃一直醒着
And Bob remained awake.
他能看到床头柜上有一把枪
He could see that there was a gun
on the nightstand.
他能想象自己手里握着冰冷的枪
He could imagine its cold nickel
inside his grip...
举起这两磅的重量，瞄准
...its two-pound weight
reached out and aimed.
我要上厕所
I need to go to the privy.
你以为你要上，但其实你不用上
You think you do, but you don't.
等祷告之后再吃
You wait for grace, now.
- 谢谢，妈妈
- 谢谢，芝，看来很好吃哦
- Thank you, Mama.
- Thank you, Zee. God, that looks good.
- 谢谢，芝
- 不客气
- Thank you, Zee.
- You're welcome.
这适合吃还是凑合？
Well, is this fit to eat or will it just do?
她做饭可是臭名远播
Woman's cooking's
always been a scandal.
她做的肉，切起来整张桌子都得晃
Cut her meat and the whole table moves.
想吃饼干吗？想要吗？
You want a biscuit?
You gonna have a biscuit?
给你黄油，来
Here's some butter.
Come on. Come on.
哦，妈的
Oh, shoot.
杰西变得越来越平易近人
And so it went,
Jesse was increasingly cavalier...
和蔼，情绪化，沉郁
...merry, moody, fey...
不可预测
...unpredictable.
他把抑郁和狂乱隐藏起来
He camouflaged his depressions
and derangements...
用高度的诚恳和风度来掩饰
...with masquerades
of extreme cordiality, courtesy...
假装对人好心好意
...and goodwill towards others.
但即使他开玩笑的时候
或者给他儿子呵痒的时候
But even as he jested,
or tickled his boy in the ribs...
杰西都会用忧郁的眼神看着鲍勃
...Jesse would look over at Bob
with melancholy eyes...
两人仿佛在进行亲密深邃的交流
...as if the two were meshed
in an intimate communication.
鲍勃坚信杰西看穿了他
Bob was certain that the man
had unriddled him...
看穿了他为什么跟来
...had seen through his reasons
for coming along...
坚信杰西能预测鲍勃任何的行动和企图
...that Jesse could forecast each of
Bob's possible moves and inclinations...
杰西只是在扮无辜
...and was only acting the innocent...
好让鲍勃放松警惕
...in order to lull Bob
into stupid tranquility and miscalculation.
你盯着我看多久了？
How long you been studying me?
你会让很多人伤心的
You're gonna break a lot of hearts.
什么意思？
How do you mean?
是份礼物
It's a present.
很沉
It's heavy.
打开看看？
Well, you gonna look inside?
今天是愚人节
It's April Fools' Day, you know.
这可不是个玩笑
It ain't no joke.
太华丽了
Oh, such extravagance.
闪亮亮的，是吧？
Don't that nickel just shine, though?
我做梦都没想过
It's more than I could hope for.
你那老破枪，说不定下次开枪的时候
I figured that granddaddy Colt
may blow into fragments...
就得崩成一块一块的了
...next time you try
to squeeze the trigger.
你也许说的对
Well, you might have something there.
汤姆，饭好了
Tom, supper's ready.
马上来，亲爱的
I'll be right there, sweetheart.
我太兴奋了，都吃不下饭了
I might be too excited to eat.
你知道约翰・纽曼・爱德华兹
曾经怎么写我吗？
You know what John Newman Edwards
once wrote about me?
他说，给我一万个人
我只能找出两个能信任的人
He said I didn't trust
two men in 10,000...
就算和这俩人一起，我还是很警惕
...and even them I was cautious around.
政府长年追捕，让我疲惫不堪
Government's sort of run me ragged.
我绕着圈子说话呢
I'm going the long way around the barn
to say that...
我是被追急了，最近有时故意刁难人
...I been feeling cornered
and just plain ornery as of late...
如果你能接受这把枪，接受我的歉意
我会很高兴的
...and I'd be pleased if you'd accept
that gun as my way of apologizing.
如果我是你，我大概会更加刁难人
Heaven knows I'd be ornerier
if I were in your position.
不，不，我的行为是不对的
No. No, I haven't been acting correctly.
我有时候都认不出自己了
Seems I hardly recognize myself
when I'm greased.
我有时候灵魂出窍
I go on journeys out of my body...
看到自己这染血的手和凶恶的脸
...and look at my red hands
and my mean face...
看着这个做了那么多错事的人
...and I wonder about that man
that's gone so wrong.
我对自己来说，都已经成了一个麻烦
I've been becoming a problem to myself.
唉
Well...
- 该吃饭了，我去洗手
- 恩，去吧
- I better wash my hands if supper's on.
- Yeah, go ahead.
他死前一天是主进圣城节
The day before he died was Palm Sunday.
汤玛斯・霍华德先生和他的夫人，
还有他们的两个孩子
And Mr. And Mrs. Thomas Howard,
their two children...
还有他们的表亲查尔斯・约翰森
...and their cousin Charles Johnson...
到第二长老会教堂参加10点的礼拜
...strolled to the Second Presbyterian
Church to attend the 10:00 service.
鲍勃留在了屋里
Bob remained at the cottage...
偷偷地从一个房间，走到另一个房间
...and slyly migrated from room to room.
他走进主人房
He walked into the master bedroom...
把里面的衣服翻了一遍
...and inventoried the clothes
on the hangers and hooks.
拿起化妆台上的一杯水，喝了一口
He sipped from the water glass
on the vanity.
闻了闻杰西枕套上的滑石粉和丁香花
He smelled the talcum and lilacs
on Jesse's pillowcase.
他的手指滑过自己的肋骨
His fingers skittered over his ribs...
想象上面像杰西那样，有两次中枪的伤疤
...to construe the scars
where Jesse was twice shot.
他把中指弄成上两个关节没了那样
He manufactured a middle finger
that was missing the top two knuckles.
想象自己34岁
He imagined himself at 34.
想象自己躺在了棺材里
He imagined himself in a coffin.
他想到各种各样
He considered possibilities...
即将成真的好事情
...and everything wonderful
that could come true.
他不会杀我们的
He's not gonna kill us.
他会的
Yeah, he is.
我会一直醒着，他就没法下手了
Well, I'll stay awake so he can't.
你在瞎想
You're imagining things.
不会去什么普拉特市
Ain't gonna be no Platte City.
杰西只是在耍我们
That's Jesse fooling with us.
睡吧，查理
Go to sleep, Charley.
[1882年4月3日]
早
Morning.
查理
Charley.
鲍勃，你要吃多少？
Bob, how much did you want to eat?
我感觉有点怪怪的
I'm feeling sort of peculiar.
为什么那么感兴趣地看着我们？
Why is it you're looking so interested?
你以为这样出去晃很聪明？
You think it's intelligent
to go out like that...
让大家都看见你的枪？
...so all creation can see your guns?
嗨
Hi.
来，看你妈妈在干吗
Come on, let's go see
what your mama's doing.
提米，开门
Timmy, get that door, would you?
- 你弄丢了一只鞋是吗，亲爱的
- 是啊
- Well, you lost your shoe, sweetheart.
- Yeah, I did.
那可麻烦了，商店也不单只卖呀
That's gonna be a problem.
They don't sell those one at a time.
我们丢了一只鞋，妈妈
We lost a shoe, Mama.
帮爸爸穿上，好吗？
Will you put that up for Daddy,
would you?
- 你在干吗，丢了一只鞋？
- 恩
- What you doing, you lose a shoe?
- Yeah.
[迪克・利都被逮捕，并已认罪]
只会往上，作为补充
It's only meant to go on top,
to complement.
我知道，有时候，我
Yeah, I know. Sometimes, l...
鲍勃，菜要凉了
Bob, everything's getting cold!
- 玛丽在哪里？
- 在外面，亲爱的
- Where's Mary?
- She's outside, darling.
玛丽？
Mary?
你说他那小脑瓜里都在想什么？
What do you think goes on
in that noggin of his?
没什么
Nothing.
我说的是他，不是你
I was talking about his mind, not yours.
哦，是啊
Oh, yeah.
哈，我明白
Oh, I get it.
啊哈
Well, hello now.
“迪克・利都被逮捕，并已认罪”
"The arrest and confession
of Dick Liddil."
不是吧
You don't say so.
真怪了
That's very strange.
上面说迪克三星期前就投降了
Says here Dick surrendered
three weeks ago.
那时候你应该在那附近吧
You must have been
right in the neighborhood.
很明显，他们是秘密行动
Well, apparently, they kept it a secret.
如果我短期内去堪萨斯市，会找人问问
If I get to Kansas City soon,
I'll ask somebody about it.
你俩准备好了吗
You two ready?
马上就好
I will be, by noon.
她要上船，航行出海
There is a ship
She sails the sea
她装了很多很多东西
She's loaded deep
As deep can be
但不及我对她的爱多
But not as deep
As the love I'm in
我不知道我是浮是沉
I know not if I sink or swim
海水广阔
The water is wide
我游不过，也没法翱翔而过
I can't cross o'er
And neither have I wings to fly
给我一只能载两个人的小船
Give me a boat
That can carry two
一起划船，我和我的爱人
Both shall row
My love and I
柔情款款
For love is gentle
And love is kind
如初开花蕾，芬芳扑鼻
Sweetest flower
When first it's new
但热情一旦冷却
But love grows old
And waxes cold
就像晨露一样枯萎
And fades away
Like the morning dew
她要上船，航行出海
There is a ship
She sails the sea
我该把枪拿下来
I guess I'll take my guns off...
别让邻居看到
...for fear the neighbors might spy them.
这画怎么那么多灰？
Don't that picture look dusty?
你…你做了什么？
What have...? What have you done?
杰西
Jesse.
杰西？
Jesse?
Jesse? Jesse?
杰西！
Jesse!
不!
No!
别，杰西
No. Jess...
回来，回来
Come back. Oh, come back.
杰西，不要！
Oh, Jesse! No!
鲍勃，是你干的吗？
Oh, Bob. Have you done this?!
我向上帝发誓，我没有
I swear to God I didn't.
是场意外，芝
It was an accident, Zee.
枪走火了
Come on. Pistol went off accidentally.
[州长：我杀了杰西・詹姆斯]
写上我的名字
Put my name.
[州长：我杀了杰西・詹姆斯。罗伯特・福特]
你做什么了？我杀了他
Why, what'd you do? I shot him.
你大概会想留着它
You might wanna keep that.
谢谢
Thank you all very much.
照片以每张２美元的价钱卖出
The resulting prints
sold for 2 dollars apiece...
好些杂志拿来做了封面
...and were the models for the lithographed
covers on a number of magazines.
成千的陌生人像着了魔一样
来到这房子来朝圣
Soon a thousand strangers were making
spellbound pilgrimages to the cottage...
到森丹法邓的冷藏室去瞻仰
...or were venerating the iced remains
in Seidenfaden's cooling room.
有个人，曾经出价３万美元，想买下
刺杀加菲尔德・詹姆士总统那杀手的尸体
The man who offered 30,000 dollars for
the body of President Garfield's assassin...
他给该市警长克雷格打了个电报，出价５万
...sent a telegram to City Marshal
Enos Craig offering 50,000...
想买下杰西・詹姆斯的遗体
...for the body
of Jesse Woodson James...
准备全国展览
...so that he could go around the country
with it...
或者至少卖给P・T・巴纳姆，在其表演里展出
（美国著名游艺节目演出的经理人）
...or at least sell it to P.T. Barnum
for his Greatest Show on Earth.
另外一张照片，拍的是这位美国著名大盗
Another photograph was taken
of the renowned American bandit...
躺在冰床上
...nestled in his bed of ice.
这张照片在小店和药房等地方都大卖
And it was this shot that was most
available in sundries and apothecaries...
大家透过立体透镜来看这照片
就像看狮身人面像
...to be viewed in a stereoscope
alongside the sphinx...
泰姬陵和罗马的地下墓室
这些名胜古迹的照片一样
...the Taj Mahal,
and the catacombs of Rome.
看啊
Hello, here!
“迪克・利都被逮捕，并已认罪”
"The arrest and confession
of Dick Liddil."
年轻人，你跟我说过
不知道迪克投降了是吧？
Young man, I thought you told me
you didn't know Dick had surrendered.
真的吗？我不知道
You mean he did? I didn't know.
但我知道我骗不了他
But I knew I had not fooled him.
他和我一样心知肚明，那一刻我准备
把他绳之于法
And he knew, as well as I, in that moment
that I intended to bring him to justice.
但他不会当着他老婆孩子的面杀我
But he would not kill me
in the presence of his wife and children.
所以他笑了，好让我放松警惕
And so he was smiling
to throw me off-guard.
哦，对阿，鲍勃
Well, it's all right, anyway, Bob.
大家都认为，鲍勃相当具有戏剧天赋
It was widely felt that
Bob possessed some acting talent...
而查理则一点天分都没有
...and Charley, not a jot.
这画怎么那么多灰呀
That picture's awful dusty.
大家希望查理不要那么垂头丧气，喃喃自语
Charley was only expected
not to slouch or mutter...
不要把这种心情传给观众
...and to transport his sicknesses
to the alley before letting them go.
就这样
And that's...
我杀了杰西・詹姆斯
...how I killed Jesse James.
到了1883年3月，认得鲍勃・福特的人
By October of 1883, Bob Ford
could be identified correctly...
已经比认得美国总统的人多了
...by more citizens than could
the president of the United States.
年仅20岁，他已经非常出名，可以媲美
杰西犯了14年偷窃罪所累积出来的名气
He was as renowned at 20 as Jesse was
after 14 years of grand larceny.
你不会勾引到我的
You won't get your hooks into me.
对了，这就对了，坐到你男朋友边上，吉贝尔
That's right. That's right.
Sit next to your boyfriend. Jezebel.
查理变得越发的迷信
Charley was increasingly superstitious...
越发相信占卜者的建议
...increasingly subject
to the advice of soothsayers...
占卜者声称能用烟斗和糊药治愈他的悲伤
...who promised to cure his miseries
with pipe smoke and poultices.
你见吉普赛人见得太多了，查理
You been spending too much time
with Gypsies, Charley.
靠
Shit.
这照片怎么那么多灰
The picture's awful dusty.
查理对杰西的演绎方式发生了变化
Something began to change
in Charley's stage portrayal of Jesse.
他的步态显得更娴熟
His gait seemed more practiced.
声音越发和那人相似，让人毛骨悚然
His voice was spookily similar
to the man's.
他新加入了一些对话
His newly suggested dialogue
was analogous...
仿佛出自杰西的创造
...to a script Jesse might have originated.
他开始用蔑视的眼神注视他的弟弟
He began to look at his younger brother
with spite...
仿佛他疑心，在以后的演出里
...as if he suspected that
in some future performance...
他将面对罗伯特・福特的真枪实弹
...he might present himself
to a live cartridge in Robert Ford's gun.
杀人犯！
Murderer!
杂种！
Cur!
懦夫！
Coward!
你想看我有多大的胆子是吗？
You wanna investigate my courage?
Do you?
来啊！来啊！
Find out! Find out!
没人来
Nobody.
懦夫！
Coward!
据他自己估计
鲍勃谋杀了杰西・詹姆斯800多次
By his own approximation, Bob
assassinated Jesse James over 800 times.
他猜，历史上没有任何人
曾这样频繁，或如此公开地
He suspected no one in history
had ever so often or so publicly...
重演一次背叛的行为
...recapitulated an act of betrayal.
鲍勃经常挑战对于懦夫的定义
Bob always challenged
the allegations of cowardice...
但查理似乎认同这些定义
...but Charley seemed
to agree with them.
他提起芝・詹姆斯太太的时候
把她说得像圣母一样
He spoke of Mrs. Zee James
as certain priests might the Madonna...
还给她写了许多发自肺腑的长信
...and composed long soul-describing letters
to her...
请求她的原谅
...begging her forgiveness...
但这些信从未寄出过
...none of which he mailed.
大家觉得，暗杀了杰西・詹姆斯的人
下场就该和查理・福特一样
Charley Ford became all that his countrymen
wanted an assassin of Jesse James to be.
杰西・詹姆斯杀了很多人
Jesse James was a man
Who killed many men
他抢了格伦代尔火车
He robbed the Glendale train
他劫富济贫
And he stole from the rich
And he gave to the poor
他身手敏捷，头脑机灵
He had a hand
And a heart and a brain
杰西有个妻子，她会为他哀悼
Well, Jesse had a wife
To mourn for his life
还有三个勇敢的儿女
Three children
They were brave
但那个肮脏的懦夫，射杀了霍华德先生
But that dirty little coward
Who shot Mr. Howard
让杰西・詹姆斯进了棺材
Has laid Jesse James in his grave
罗伯特・福特，这肮脏的小懦夫
It was Robert Ford
That dirty little coward
我想知道他的感受
I wonder how does he feel
他吃杰西的饭，睡杰西的床
For he ate at Jesse's bread
And he slept in Jesse's bed
却让可怜的杰西进了棺材
And he laid poor Jesse in his grave
杰西有个妻子，她会为他哀悼
Well, Jesse had a wife
To mourn for his life
还有三个勇敢的儿女
Three children
They were brave
但那个肮脏的懦夫，射杀了霍华德先生
But that dirty little coward
Who shot Mr. Howard
让可怜的杰西进了棺材
Has laid poor Jesse in his grave
我就是罗伯特・福特
I'm Robert Ford.
是两个孩子，不是三个
It was two children, not three.
嘿
Hey.
回家去，好吗
You get yourself home, son, okay?
出去，滚出我的地方
Come on. Get out of here.
Get out of my place.
他生气极了的时候
He thought, at his angriest...
会想去见杰西杀害的人的家属
...about visiting the kin
of Jesse's slaughtered victims:
普拉茨堡的威廉太太
Mrs. William Westfall in Plattsburg...
克莱县的崴墨一家
...the Wymore family in Clay County...
甚至是马萨诸塞州北田的
约瑟夫・黑伍德的遗孀
...perhaps even Mrs. Joseph Heywood
in Northfield, Minnesota.
他想到这些人的家里
告诉他们他叫罗伯特・詹姆斯
He would go to their homes
and give his name as Robert Ford...
告诉他们他杀了杰西・詹姆斯
...the man who killed Jesse James.
他想象他们会对他充满感激之情
He imagined they would
be grateful to him.
他只对多莱西・伊凡思坦白道出了真相
It was only with Dorothy Evans
that Bob spoke revealingly or plainly...
告诉她一些他以前都不知道自己知道的事情
...and it was with her that he spoke of
things he didn't know he knew.
他告诉她，他对射杀和后事都没有真实的记忆
He told her that he had no real memory
of the shooting and its aftermath.
他只记得，举起了那把杰西给他的枪
He could remember lifting the gun
that Jesse had given him...
然后就到耶稣受难日了，他看到了葬礼安排
...and then it was Good Friday and he was
reading about the funeral proceedings...
仿佛事情已经过去了很久
...as if they'd happened a long time ago.
你为什么杀了他？
Why did you kill him?
他要杀我
Well, he was gonna kill me.
那唯一的原因就是你害怕了？
So you were scared
and that's the only reason?
对
Yeah.
还有赏金
And the reward money.
你想我换个话题吗？
Do you want me to change the subject?
你知道我曾经期待什么吗？
You know what I expected?
掌声
Applause.
我那时候才20岁，我不知道别人会怎么看
I was only 20 years old then.
I couldn't see how it would look to people.
事情竟变成这样，我很吃惊
I was surprised by what happened.
他们没有鼓掌
They didn't applaud.
他为自己的吹嘘
He was ashamed of his boasting...
自己假装的勇敢无畏而感到羞耻
...his pretensions of courage
and ruthlessness.
他为自己的冷血无情
He was sorry about his cold-bloodedness,
his dispassion...
为自己无法表达自己真实的感情而充满愧疚
...his inability to express
what he now believed was the case:
他很后悔杀了杰西
That he truly regretted killing Jesse...
他非常想念他
...that he missed the man
as much as anybody...
他希望，他不是非要杀了杰西来保命
...and wished his murder
hadn't been necessary.
即使当他在自己的酒吧里穿行
Even as he circulated his saloon...
他也知道他走过之后，这些人的笑容就会消失
...he knew that the smiles disappeared
when he passed by.
他收到很多很多恶意信件
He received so many menacing letters...
到最后他读的时候除了好奇，就没有别的反应了
...that he could read them
without any reaction except curiosity.
他整天呆在屋里，翻着扑克牌
He kept to his apartment all day,
flipping over playing cards...
在每张K和J牌里注视自己的命运
...looking at his destiny
in every king and jack.
8号下午1点，爱德华・奥凯利来了
Edward O'Kelly came up from Bachelor
at 1 p.m. On the 8th.
他没有什么大计，没有策略
He had no grand scheme, no strategy...
没有和警方订任何协议
...no agreement with higher authorities...
心里只是暗暗期待着荣誉
...nothing beyond
a vague longing for glory...
和向罗伯特・福特报复的心情
...and a generalized wish
for revenge against Robert Ford.
- 昨晚怎样？
- 不坏
- How'd it go last night?
- Not so bad.
另一支
The other one.
爱德华・奥凯利将因二级谋杀
Edward O'Kelly would be ordered
to serve a life sentence...
在科罗拉多惩戒所被判终身监禁
...in the Colorado Penitentiary
for second-degree murder.
最终，超过7000人签名
Over 7000 signatures
would eventually be gathered...
请求释放奥凯利
...on a petition asking for
O'Kelly's release...
1902年，州长詹姆斯・B・奥曼将其释放
...and in 1902, Governor James B. Orman
would pardon the man.
你不应该戴那个领带夹的，蛋白石不吉祥
You shouldn't be wearing that stickpin
again there, Bob. Opals are unlucky.
我运气本身也不好
蛋白石可能还能给我转运呢
My luck's not very good as it is. I don't
think an opal's gonna change that much.
我听到了
I hear you.
没有人会给鲍勃念颂词
There would be no eulogies for Bob...
杂货店也不会卖他遗体的照片
...no photographs of his body
would be sold in sundries stores...
没有人会在雨天涌到街上去看他的葬礼行列
...no people would crowd the streets
in the rain to see his funeral cortege...
没人会给他写传记
...no biographies would be written
about him...
没有人会给孩子起他的名字
...no children named after him.
没有人会付25美分去看他长大的那个屋子
No one would ever pay 25 cents
to stand in the rooms he grew up in.
你好啊，鲍勃
Hello, Bob.
枪声响起，艾拉・梅会尖叫
The shotgun would ignite,
and Ella Mae would scream...
但罗伯特・福特只会躺在地板上
盯着天花板
...but Robert Ford would only lay
on the floor and look at the ceiling...
他的眼睛逐渐失去光彩
...the light going out of his eyes...
他没想到该说什么话
...before he could find the right words.
片名：神枪手之死
TLF中文字幕站
http://tlfsubs.eastgame.net
[ENGLISH]